<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Opinion on Boaz Sobrado's Website</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/series/opinion/</link><description>Recent content in Opinion on Boaz Sobrado's Website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&amp;copy; 2022 &lt;a href="https://www.boazsobrado.com/">Boaz Sobrado&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2023 13:11:22 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://boazsobrado.com/series/opinion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Donald Trump, Paul Le Roux and the Dutch East India Company - Part 2</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2023/04/23/donald-trump-paul-le-roux-and-the-dutch-east-india-company-part-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2023 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2023/04/23/donald-trump-paul-le-roux-and-the-dutch-east-india-company-part-2/</guid><description>The conditions which lead to the rise (and fall) of company states discussed in Part I may seem distant to us in the 21st century. Nation states are as powerful as ever, and social &amp;amp; technological conditions seem very different to the age of exploration in which these entities thrived. For example, in the 1700s it took orders from European rulers months to arrive in the far East. Companies had considerable leeway to do as they felt fit.</description></item><item><title>Donald Trump, Paul Le Roux and the Dutch East India Company - Part 1</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2023/03/17/donald-trump-paul-le-roux-and-the-dutch-east-india-company-part-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2023/03/17/donald-trump-paul-le-roux-and-the-dutch-east-india-company-part-1/</guid><description>In January 2021, powerful tech companies Facebook, Twitter and Google moved to censor President Donald Trump. Whether or not DJT deserved this ban is irrelevant for the purposes of this essay. It is the sheer power of for-profit entities that is of interest. Tech companies were free to gag the sitting a head of state. The head of state of the most powerful country in the world. A man who, for all his flaws, won millions of votes and had a political mandate (at least on paper) to lead a superpower.</description></item><item><title>Crypto Should Disrupt Current Anti-Money Laundering Practices, Not Adopt Them</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2022/03/31/crypto-should-disrupt-current-anti-money-laundering-practices-not-adopt-them/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2022/03/31/crypto-should-disrupt-current-anti-money-laundering-practices-not-adopt-them/</guid><description>Originally published in CoinDesk
Until the early 20th century, highly respected doctors would routinely engage in bloodletting to cure ailments ranging from acne to tuberculosis. While we have left bloodletting behind, we are still engaging in putatively helpful, but veritably destructive practices.
Modern know-your-customer/anti-money laundering (KYC/AML) regulations are equivalent to financial bloodletting today: They do little good and may cause a lot of harm. Yet whether we like it or not, the KYC/AML nightmare is coming to crypto.</description></item><item><title>GameFi’s Promise and Reality Are Still Worlds Apart</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2022/03/08/gamefis-promise-and-reality-are-still-worlds-apart/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2022/03/08/gamefis-promise-and-reality-are-still-worlds-apart/</guid><description>Originally published in CoinDesk
Among crypto&amp;rsquo;s hottest trends is GameFi, which brings Web 3&amp;rsquo;s advantages to gaming. Web 3&amp;rsquo;s meaning varies by individual but reflects rising demand among people who are spending more time and money in meta worlds to own their virtual assets, free from the interference of platform developers.
But are strong in-game property rights compatible with fun, escapist experiences that users are seeking?
Skeptics are not convinced. They say that GameFi games are not fun but rather merely repackaged versions of the worst elements of decentralized finance (DeFi).</description></item><item><title>Are Crypto Investors Savvy or Suckers? The UK’s Tax and Financial Regulators Don’t Agree</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2022/02/24/are-crypto-investors-savvy-or-suckers-the-uks-tax-and-financial-regulators-dont-agree/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2022/02/24/are-crypto-investors-savvy-or-suckers-the-uks-tax-and-financial-regulators-dont-agree/</guid><description>Originally published in CoinDesk Magazine
Are crypto investors financially savvy investors who are capable of understanding the nuances of blockchain, Web 3 and decentralized finance? Or are they mostly vulnerable, uneducated speculators who are being taken advantage of?
The Financial Conduct Authority (FCA), the U.K.&amp;rsquo;s financial regulator, believes they are the latter, while the U.K.&amp;rsquo;s tax collection agency, HM Revenue &amp;amp; Customs, or HMRC, believes they are the former. While the agencies have issued a few helpful guidelines, their differing opinions underscore a fundamental inability to provide more sweeping and effective oversight that would protect consumers and ensure the industry&amp;rsquo;s development.</description></item><item><title>We All Need to Stop Only Seeing the Dark Side of Crypto</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2021/12/19/we-all-need-to-stop-only-seeing-the-dark-side-of-crypto/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2021 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2021/12/19/we-all-need-to-stop-only-seeing-the-dark-side-of-crypto/</guid><description>Originally published in Wired Magazine
IN 2021, BITCOIN went mainstream. Wall Street set its eyes on the world of crypto, with hotshot investors like hedge funder Paul Tudor Jones leading the pack; The Economist went from calling the cryptocurrency &amp;ldquo;useless&amp;rdquo; in 2018 to arguing that it belongs in most portfolios; tech CEOs Jack Dorsey and Elon Musk gamely crossed swords about Bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s merits at a conference run by an asset management firm. Popular opinion lags a bit: Many people still believe cryptocurrency is a giant, global get-rich-quick scheme.</description></item><item><title>DeFi needs a Silk Road moment</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2020/12/11/defi-needs-a-silk-road-moment/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2020/12/11/defi-needs-a-silk-road-moment/</guid><description>This article was originally published as an Op-Ed on CoinDesk
Mainstream criminal adoption would prove that decentralized finance (DeFi) is building tools with real utility, because if there&amp;rsquo;s any one group that is both underserved in their access to sophisticated financial products and willing to pay huge premiums to acquire them, it&amp;rsquo;s criminals. The Silk Road was launched in February of 2011 and quickly became the first example of Bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s product-market fit. While some proponents of cryptocurrencies argue that today criminal activities are a small percentage of all cryptocurrency transactions, censorship resistance is one of the key features of all decentralized technologies and criminals have played a part in crypto&amp;rsquo;s wider adoption.</description></item><item><title>Why Cuba is primed for bitcoin adoption</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2020/12/11/why-cuba-is-primed-for-bitcoin-adoption/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2020/12/11/why-cuba-is-primed-for-bitcoin-adoption/</guid><description>This article was originally published as an Op-Ed on Decrypt
Cuba is having one of its worst years in recent memory&amp;mdash;but, as a consequence, a perfect storm is brewing on the island nation with regard to Bitcoin adoption.
Cubans live under a high level of financial censorship, as well as rampant inflation. Meanwhile, their access to foreign currencies has been heavily curtailed this year due to COVID and US sanctions. This has increased the appeal of cryptocurrencies, many of which act as censorship-resistant stores of value.</description></item></channel></rss>