<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Hacking on Boaz Sobrado's Website</title><link>https://sobradob.github.io/personal_site_2022/series/hacking/</link><description>Recent content in Hacking on Boaz Sobrado's Website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&amp;copy; 2022 &lt;a href="https://www.boazsobrado.com/">Boaz Sobrado&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 13:11:22 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sobradob.github.io/personal_site_2022/series/hacking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Automating my business</title><link>https://sobradob.github.io/personal_site_2022/blog/2019/08/12/automating-my-business/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://sobradob.github.io/personal_site_2022/blog/2019/08/12/automating-my-business/</guid><description>As a small business owner keeping track of things can be surprisingly difficult: how you spend your money, who owes you money, who you owe money, what are your expenses, margins, operating costs&amp;hellip;
If you have multiple revenue streams from multiple platforms, you can quickly reach a point where you ignore basic things, like for example how much you are making exactly. Specially when you are focused on numerous other things as you try to scale your business.</description></item><item><title>Where I was in 2018</title><link>https://sobradob.github.io/personal_site_2022/blog/2019/01/13/where-i-was-in-2018/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 22:52:56 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://sobradob.github.io/personal_site_2022/blog/2019/01/13/where-i-was-in-2018/</guid><description>I spent a lot of time this year on the road. I started 2018 on a tropical beach in the Phillipines and ended it in Lisbon, with a lot of trips in between. Given that I spent a good part of this year playing around with maps for my thesis, I thought it would be fun to use my Google Location Services data to animate my movement this year. Here is the result:
How did I make this animation?</description></item><item><title>Cuba’s short term property rental market 2017-2018</title><link>https://sobradob.github.io/personal_site_2022/blog/2018/08/11/cubas-short-term-property-rental-market-2017-2018/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2018 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://sobradob.github.io/personal_site_2022/blog/2018/08/11/cubas-short-term-property-rental-market-2017-2018/</guid><description>In July of 2017 President Trump announced with much fanfare a new policy towards Cuba. This was following the Obama administrations &amp;ldquo;thaw&amp;rdquo; in Cuban-American bilateral relations, which had lead to a noticable rise in Americas visiting the island. Then more bad news for the Cuban tourism industry:
sonic warfare in the news hurricanes All of this together had a noticable impact on the Cuban tourism sector. Official Cuban statistics show that tourism numbers are going up.</description></item><item><title>How to generate a Bitcoin vanity address using a Mac</title><link>https://sobradob.github.io/personal_site_2022/blog/2018/08/11/how-to-generate-a-bitcoin-vanity-address-using-a-mac/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2018 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://sobradob.github.io/personal_site_2022/blog/2018/08/11/how-to-generate-a-bitcoin-vanity-address-using-a-mac/</guid><description>A bitcoin vanity address is an address that starts in a particular way. Here is an example:
Once I saw these addresses exist, I obviously wanted one. There are many websites that help you generate a vanity address, however it involves a trusted third party. Nick Szabo doesn&amp;rsquo;t like trusted third parties.
There are clear, up to date instructions on how to do this on Windows. The only thing I found on Mac was this blogpost from 2013.</description></item><item><title>Leaflet timeline in R</title><link>https://sobradob.github.io/personal_site_2022/blog/2018/02/08/leaflet-timeline-in-r/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 15:52:58 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://sobradob.github.io/personal_site_2022/blog/2018/02/08/leaflet-timeline-in-r/</guid><description>Leaflet is a powerful tool for visualasing spatial data in R. However, after much googling I could not find an easy way to create a timeline to visualise changes in time. Therefore, I decided to create a simple shiny app that does it.
Raw Android GPS Movements Code The code below takes raw location measurements from my Android phone visualises them over time. The size of the circle is the confidence interval of the measurement. Before you go and try to find me at those spots, I no longer live there!</description></item><item><title>Time Series analysis for Facebook message volume</title><link>https://sobradob.github.io/personal_site_2022/blog/2017/12/17/time-series-analysis-for-facebook-message-volume/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2017 22:52:56 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://sobradob.github.io/personal_site_2022/blog/2017/12/17/time-series-analysis-for-facebook-message-volume/</guid><description>Introduction to the data set The data is the amount of Facebook messages a user (me) sent and received between 2011 and 2016. The data was exported from Facebook, converted from HTML to JSON and subsequently read into R. For more details on how this was done, please consult here.
The original data source contains 413,101 timestamps and messages between 2008 and 2016. The volume of messages is very low between 2008-2011, and highly atypical to the rest of the series, so it was not considered in the sample.</description></item><item><title>Time Series analysis for Facebook message volume</title><link>https://sobradob.github.io/personal_site_2022/blog/2017/12/01/time-series-analysis-for-facebook-message-volume/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 15:52:58 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://sobradob.github.io/personal_site_2022/blog/2017/12/01/time-series-analysis-for-facebook-message-volume/</guid><description>Introduction to the data set
The data is the amount of Facebook messages a user (me) sent and received between 2011 and 2016. The data was exported from Facebook, converted from HTML to JSON and subsequently read into R. For more details on how this was done, please consult here.
The original data source contains 413,101 timestamps and messages between 2008 and 2016. The volume of messages is very low between 2008-2011, and highly atypical to the rest of the series, so it was not considered in the sample.</description></item><item><title>Implementing a Kalman filter in R for Android GPS measurements</title><link>https://sobradob.github.io/personal_site_2022/blog/2017/08/29/implementing-a-kalman-filter-in-r-for-android-gps-measurements/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2017 17:58:21 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://sobradob.github.io/personal_site_2022/blog/2017/08/29/implementing-a-kalman-filter-in-r-for-android-gps-measurements/</guid><description>The problem I downloaded my data from Google Take-Out and have been playing around with it for my thesis. This is roughly what the data looks like after some pre-processing:
lon lat accuracy 5.115447 52.10574 877 5.115447 52.10574 877 5.113952 52.10451 18 5.115447 52.10574 877 5.115447 52.10574 877 5.115447 52.10574 877 As soon as I looked into it I realised there were some issues with the measurements. They were all over the place!
The circles are the measurements (with their radius representing the accuracy and the center being the point) and lines connect these measurements in time.</description></item><item><title>Costa Rican Saints</title><link>https://sobradob.github.io/personal_site_2022/blog/2017/08/18/costa-rican-saints/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2017 22:22:16 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://sobradob.github.io/personal_site_2022/blog/2017/08/18/costa-rican-saints/</guid><description>One of the first things a traveller notices when going to Costa Rica is that almost every town or city is named after a Saint. Growing up in Costa Rica, I just assumed this was something true of all Latin American countries, a legacy of Spanish colonial times. California has San Jose, San Fransisco, etc. I thought it was like that from California to Argentina.
After some travelling in Latin America I realised this was simply not true.</description></item><item><title>You are wasting your time with spreadsheets</title><link>https://sobradob.github.io/personal_site_2022/blog/2016/11/13/you-are-wasting-your-time-with-spreadsheets/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 15:52:58 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://sobradob.github.io/personal_site_2022/blog/2016/11/13/you-are-wasting-your-time-with-spreadsheets/</guid><description>This week I had an interesting conversation (as interesting as these conversations can get) about the use of spreadsheets in business. I am still a little bit surprised by how often they are used for things they are not really good for. Now, I don’t want to write about how there are better alternatives to spreadsheets. Instead, I’d like to illustrate how powerful non-spreadsheet tools are by describing a task I completed this week using R.</description></item><item><title>How to get your Facebook messages into R</title><link>https://sobradob.github.io/personal_site_2022/blog/2016/10/29/how-to-get-your-facebook-messages-into-r/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2016 15:52:58 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://sobradob.github.io/personal_site_2022/blog/2016/10/29/how-to-get-your-facebook-messages-into-r/</guid><description>It is a truism that we live in the information age, yet on a day to day basis we engage remarkably little with insights on the personal information we create. Sure, Netflix shows you films you want to see, Amazon offers books you want to buy and Facebook shows you pictures of cats with boobs or whatever it is you tend to click on, but explicit purpose of that is to get your money. What about using all that data to gain insights on who you are, who your friends are, what you tend to talk about?</description></item><item><title>How I made this website - tutorial</title><link>https://sobradob.github.io/personal_site_2022/blog/2016/04/20/how-i-made-this-website-tutorial/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 14:12:49 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://sobradob.github.io/personal_site_2022/blog/2016/04/20/how-i-made-this-website-tutorial/</guid><description>Theory As our activities are increasingly organised online – from business through voting to leisure time – knowing how to write (or even just understand) code is an increasingly coveted skill. Its benefits range wide; if you can code you will get a better job, improve your analytical skills, make work processes easier and cheaper.
These reasons led us – Dora and Boaz, authors of this article – to set up our websites as a means of learning and practising a bit of coding.</description></item><item><title>Using Google Maps API: Mol Bubi Competition</title><link>https://sobradob.github.io/personal_site_2022/blog/2015/11/05/using-google-maps-api-mol-bubi-competition/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2015 11:36:16 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://sobradob.github.io/personal_site_2022/blog/2015/11/05/using-google-maps-api-mol-bubi-competition/</guid><description>A few friends and I are involved in the Budapest public bicycle data science competition. As of right now we are in the top ten, although in all honesty, it hasn&amp;rsquo;t really started yet. We signed a non-disclosure agreement, so I cannot really share any cool details. What I can share however, is the function I wrote in R to get calculate the distances and duration of bike trips using Google Maps&amp;rsquo; API.
#distance calucations #### This script uses RCurl and RJSONIO to download data from Google's API library(RCurl) library(RJSONIO) #define api key as: api&amp;lt;-&amp;quot;YOURAPI&amp;quot; #the function assumes address input in following dataframe: #lat1,lng1,lat2,lng2 DistDur &amp;lt;- function(address,time = as.</description></item><item><title>Do stupid people make more spelling mistakes? An analysis with R.</title><link>https://sobradob.github.io/personal_site_2022/blog/2015/10/20/do-stupid-people-make-more-spelling-mistakes-an-analysis-with-r./</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2015 10:23:55 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://sobradob.github.io/personal_site_2022/blog/2015/10/20/do-stupid-people-make-more-spelling-mistakes-an-analysis-with-r./</guid><description>English orthography is a tricky topic. Most people learning English (and a great number of native speakers) are puzzled by a written language with an utter disregard for phonemic representation. It is therefore very worrying that individuals intuitively assume making orthographic mistakes is a sign of low intelligence or unprofessionalism. In this post we are going to show how we looked into the relationship of IQ and orthography using R. We are going to need two things:</description></item></channel></rss>