<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Facebook on Boaz Sobrado's Website</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/categories/facebook/</link><description>Recent content in Facebook on Boaz Sobrado's Website</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&amp;copy; 2024 &lt;a href="https://www.boazsobrado.com/">Boaz Sobrado&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 15:52:58 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://boazsobrado.com/categories/facebook/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Time Series analysis for Facebook message volume</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2017/12/01/time-series-analysis-for-facebook-message-volume/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 15:52:58 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2017/12/01/time-series-analysis-for-facebook-message-volume/</guid><description>&lt;h2>Introduction to the data set&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The data is the amount of Facebook messages a user (me) sent and received between 2011 and 2016. The data was exported from Facebook, converted from HTML to JSON and subsequently read into R. For more details on how this was done, please consult &lt;a href="http://boazsobrado.com/blog/2016/10/29/how-to-get-your-facebook-messages-into-r/">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The original data source contains 413,101 timestamps and messages between 2008 and 2016. The volume of messages is very low between 2008-2011, and highly atypical to the rest of the series, so it was not considered in the sample. An example is shown below:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to get your Facebook messages into R</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2016/10/29/how-to-get-your-facebook-messages-into-r/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2016 15:52:58 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2016/10/29/how-to-get-your-facebook-messages-into-r/</guid><description>&lt;p>It is a truism that we live in the information age, yet on a day to day basis we engage remarkably little with insights on the personal information we create. Sure, Netflix shows you films you want to see, Amazon offers books you want to buy and Facebook shows you pictures of cats with boobs or whatever it is you tend to click on, but explicit purpose of that is to get your money. What about using all that data to gain insights on who you are, who your friends are, what you tend to talk about? Introspection has a long history, but &lt;a href="https://www.wikiwand.com/en/Wilhelm_Wundt">Wundt&lt;/a> wasn&amp;rsquo;t particularly data-driven.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Donald Trump and Zuckerberg's Matrix</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2016/02/29/donald-trump-and-zuckerbergs-matrix/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Feb 2016 22:22:16 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2016/02/29/donald-trump-and-zuckerbergs-matrix/</guid><description>&lt;p>Prediction markets have the Republican nomination for President of the USA going to billionaire reality TV host and megalomaniac Donald Trump. On the other side of the aisle, self-described socialist Sanders is making Hillary Clinton’s campaign sweat. This isn’t “politics as usual” for anyone except the writers of The Simpsons.
&lt;img src="http://www.snopes.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/SimpsonsTrumpEpisode2000.jpg" alt="img">
According to the party decides theory (or at least my interpretation of &lt;a href="http://fivethirtyeight.com/tag/the-party-decides/">Nate Silver’s interpretation&lt;/a>) the party, as a loose coalition of opinion forming individuals, can heavily weigh in on who gets nominated. Yet they took so long to settle on Rubio that Trump is now the likeliest candidate. Perhaps this is a sign of the GOP’s weakness, or perhaps they hate Cruz more than they hate Trump. These are all strong arguments that have been well &lt;a href="http://fivethirtyeight.com/features/dont-assume-conservatives-will-rally-behind-trump/">argued elsewhere&lt;/a>, but I would like to present an alternative one: the party just isn’t as effective at forming opinions as it used to be, because social media has created a pervasive platform for radicalisation.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>