<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Opinion on Boaz Sobrado's Website</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/tags/opinion/</link><description>Recent content in Opinion on Boaz Sobrado's Website</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&amp;copy; 2024 &lt;a href="https://www.boazsobrado.com/">Boaz Sobrado&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 13:11:22 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://boazsobrado.com/tags/opinion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A salaryman worth his salt</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2024/03/24/a-salaryman-worth-his-salt/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2024/03/24/a-salaryman-worth-his-salt/</guid><description>&lt;p>Do you really know where your salary comes from?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The word &amp;ldquo;salary&amp;rdquo; comes from the Latin word &amp;ldquo;salarium,&amp;rdquo; which originally referred to a soldier&amp;rsquo;s allowance for the purchase of salt. Salt was a valuable commodity up until modern times, often used as a preservative and for seasoning. Sometimes even as a currency in trade. The Latin word &amp;ldquo;salarium&amp;rdquo; is derived from &amp;ldquo;sal,&amp;rdquo; meaning salt. The median UK salary after tax is about £2400 a month, which buys about 2 tons of salt.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Tulip Craze Conspiracy</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2024/03/23/the-tulip-craze-conspiracy/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2024/03/23/the-tulip-craze-conspiracy/</guid><description>&lt;p>Have you heard of the Dutch Tulip craze? If so, you&amp;rsquo;ve likely fallen victim to centuries old propaganda. The Dutch tulip bubble of the 17th century never actually happened, at least not the way it is understood in popular culture.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The popular understanding of the tulip craze goes as follows:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Between 1634 and 1637 Dutch people were engaged in a speculative fever, whereby a wide cross-section of Dutch society gambled on the price of tulips. Peasants who speculated correctly on the price of tulips ended up wealthier than lords. At some point in February 1637 people realised that tulips were actually worthless and the resulting crash tanked the economy.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Are we living in an advertising economy?</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2024/02/23/are-we-living-in-an-advertising-economy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2024/02/23/are-we-living-in-an-advertising-economy/</guid><description>&lt;p>If the economy is struggling, why are stocks at all time highs? Advertising! (And AI but lets ignore that for now).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>During Covid years, consumers suddenly became cash rich. They got generous government transfers and couldn’t spend money on going out. They paid down their debts and bought goods &amp;amp; services online.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once they realised consumers had money to spend and were willing to spend it, companies started raising their prices to improve their margins. They did so regardless of whether they were impacted by any inflationary pressures. Consumers were happy to pay it… until…&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Numbers Behind Small Loans</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2023/09/23/the-numbers-behind-small-loans/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2023 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2023/09/23/the-numbers-behind-small-loans/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Code of Hammurabi (c. 1700 B.C.E.) is one of the earliest known legal texts. It contains the first known formulation of &lt;em>lex talonis&lt;/em>, the principle of exact retaliation. Today people are most familiar with its Biblical version: &lt;em>an eye for an eye&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Code of Hammurabi is also the first known attempt of a regulator to cap lending interest rates:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>If a merchant lends grain at interest, for one gur he shall receive one hundred sila as interest (33 percent); if he lends money at interest, for one shekel of silver he shall receive one-fifth of a shekel as interest (20 percent).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Old Age Originations</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2023/07/16/old-age-originations/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2023/07/16/old-age-originations/</guid><description>&lt;p>In my &lt;a href="https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2023/06/17/from-subprime-crisis-to-the-newly-prime-crisis/">previous post&lt;/a> I discussed how credit score inflation contributed to the flurry of US mortgage originations in 2020-2021. As you can see from the chart below, the scale of the mortgage boom was truly unprecedented:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img alt="Mortgage origination by credit score" src="https://boazsobrado.com/images/mortgage_origination_credit_score.png">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another part of the story is the quantity of older people taking out mortgages, which was vastly higher than in any previous period. The rise of the 70+ cohort is particularly exceptional.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The vast majority of these mortgages will not be paid back by the original mortgage holder. The average mortgage term in the US is 30 years. Life expectancy at birth is 79 for women and 73 for men. Healthy men reaching 70 can expect to live till 85. Very few will make it to 100+.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>From subprime crisis to the newly prime crisis</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2023/06/17/from-subprime-crisis-to-the-newly-prime-crisis/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2023 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2023/06/17/from-subprime-crisis-to-the-newly-prime-crisis/</guid><description>&lt;p>What if credit scores have misled banks into the next lending crisis? The Global Financial Crisis of 2007 is often blamed on irresponsible lending. Lenders offered large amounts of credit to &amp;ldquo;subprime&amp;rdquo; customers. Subprime being a fancy term for people with poor credit scores, who are less likely to pay the loans back.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>According to &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2007%E2%80%932008_financial_crisis">Wikipedia&lt;/a>:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The 2007–2008 financial crisis, or Global Financial Crisis (GFC), was a severe worldwide economic crisis that occurred in the early 21st century. It was the most serious financial crisis since the Great Depression (1929). Predatory lending targeting low-income homebuyers, excessive risk-taking by global financial institutions, and the bursting of the United States housing bubble culminated in a &amp;lsquo;perfect storm&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pricing, Profit and Paternalism</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2023/05/12/pricing-profit-and-paternalism/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2023 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2023/05/12/pricing-profit-and-paternalism/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>What do you do when you discover your most profitable customers are using your product wrong? This is a discussion on pricing, the morals of marketing and the costs of compliance.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="a-thought-experiment">A thought experiment&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>You decide to leave your corporate 9-5 job and start a simple business in short term storage. The value proposition is fairly clear: you will rent out storage space to people who need a place to leave their stuff for a few days, weeks or even up to 3 months.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Donald Trump, Paul Le Roux and the Dutch East India Company - Part 2</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2023/04/23/donald-trump-paul-le-roux-and-the-dutch-east-india-company-part-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2023 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2023/04/23/donald-trump-paul-le-roux-and-the-dutch-east-india-company-part-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>The conditions which lead to the rise (and fall) of company states discussed in &lt;a href="https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2023/03/17/donald-trump-paul-le-roux-and-the-dutch-east-india-company-part-1/">Part I&lt;/a> may seem distant to us in the 21st century. Nation states are as powerful as ever, and social &amp;amp; technological conditions seem very different to the age of exploration in which these entities thrived.  For example, in the 1700s it took orders from European rulers months to arrive in the far East. Companies had considerable leeway to do as they felt fit. Today we have instant messaging across the globe 24/7.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Donald Trump, Paul Le Roux and the Dutch East India Company - Part 1</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2023/03/17/donald-trump-paul-le-roux-and-the-dutch-east-india-company-part-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2023/03/17/donald-trump-paul-le-roux-and-the-dutch-east-india-company-part-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>In January 2021, powerful tech companies Facebook, Twitter and Google moved to censor President Donald Trump. Whether or not DJT deserved this ban is irrelevant for the purposes of this essay. It is the sheer power of for-profit entities that is of interest. Tech companies were free to gag the sitting a head of state. The head of state of the most powerful country in the world. A man who, for all his flaws, won millions of votes and had a political mandate (at least on paper) to lead a superpower. This level of corporate power is unprecedented in our lifetimes, and it rang alarm bells amongst political leaders across the world. Even politically distant and moderate politicians, such as Angela Merkel, &lt;a href="https://www.ft.com/content/6146b352-6b40-48ef-b10b-a34ad585b91a">voiced their concern&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>