<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>opinion on Boaz Sobrado's Website</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/tags/opinion/</link><description>Recent content in opinion on Boaz Sobrado's Website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&amp;copy; 2022 &lt;a href="https://www.boazsobrado.com/">Boaz Sobrado&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2023 13:11:22 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://boazsobrado.com/tags/opinion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Donald Trump, Paul Le Roux and the Dutch East India Company - Part 2</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2023/04/23/donald-trump-paul-le-roux-and-the-dutch-east-india-company-part-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2023 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2023/04/23/donald-trump-paul-le-roux-and-the-dutch-east-india-company-part-2/</guid><description>The conditions which lead to the rise (and fall) of company states discussed in Part I may seem distant to us in the 21st century. Nation states are as powerful as ever, and social &amp;amp; technological conditions seem very different to the age of exploration in which these entities thrived. For example, in the 1700s it took orders from European rulers months to arrive in the far East. Companies had considerable leeway to do as they felt fit.</description></item><item><title>Donald Trump, Paul Le Roux and the Dutch East India Company - Part 1</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2023/03/17/donald-trump-paul-le-roux-and-the-dutch-east-india-company-part-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2023/03/17/donald-trump-paul-le-roux-and-the-dutch-east-india-company-part-1/</guid><description>In January 2021, powerful tech companies Facebook, Twitter and Google moved to censor President Donald Trump. Whether or not DJT deserved this ban is irrelevant for the purposes of this essay. It is the sheer power of for-profit entities that is of interest. Tech companies were free to gag the sitting a head of state. The head of state of the most powerful country in the world. A man who, for all his flaws, won millions of votes and had a political mandate (at least on paper) to lead a superpower.</description></item></channel></rss>