<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Books on Boaz Sobrado's Website</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/categories/books/</link><description>Recent content in Books on Boaz Sobrado's Website</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&amp;copy; 2024 &lt;a href="https://www.boazsobrado.com/">Boaz Sobrado&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2016 09:48:37 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://boazsobrado.com/categories/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Boaz's Review of Books: Violence, elaborate lies and a literary journey through China and Africa</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2016/04/18/boazs-review-of-books-violence-elaborate-lies-and-a-literary-journey-through-china-and-africa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2016 09:48:37 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2016/04/18/boazs-review-of-books-violence-elaborate-lies-and-a-literary-journey-through-china-and-africa/</guid><description>&lt;p>The books I finished reading recently that I thought might be interesting to comment upon were Steven Pinker’s &lt;a href="https://www.wikiwand.com/en/The_Better_Angels_of_Our_Nature">The better Angels of Our Nature&lt;/a>, Mo Yan’s &lt;a href="https://www.wikiwand.com/en/Big_Breasts_and_Wide_Hips">Big Breast’s and Wide Hips&lt;/a>, Kapuscinski’s &lt;a href="https://www.wikiwand.com/en/The_Shadow_of_the_Sun">The Shadow of the Sun&lt;/a>, Robert Mazur’s &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/6657841-the-infiltrator">Infiltrator&lt;/a> and David Maurer’s &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/403452.The_Big_Con">Big Con&lt;/a> .
&lt;br>
&lt;br>
Steven Pinker, a psychologist at Harvard, wrote a &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/review/R2F21HEM6W56FI/ref=cm_cr_dp_title?ie=UTF8&amp;ASIN=0141034645&amp;channel=detail-glance&amp;nodeID=266239&amp;store=books">(way too long)&lt;/a> book to argue the world is becoming less, not more violent. What about ISIS, Ukraine, gang warfare and mass shootings? Terrible things, but not nearly as violent as the Thirty Year War or Genghis Khan. This is based on relative homicide rates, or simply put: how many people die a violent death as a percentage of the population. You might be one of those paleo diet people who idealises the “peaceful” times of back when we were hunter-gatherers, living in the comfort of nature eating fruits off trees and fish out of the water. It turns out that was the most violent time we ever lived. In fact, even in the last 50 years there has been a substantial decrease in violence in the world. Even terrorism isn’t what it &lt;a href="http://globalriskinsights.com/2016/03/19640/">used to be&lt;/a>.
&lt;br>
&lt;br>
![terrorist attacks in Europe] (&lt;a href="http://i0.wp.com/globalriskinsights.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/terrorist_attacks_in_western_europe_since_1970_n-557x1024.jpg">http://i0.wp.com/globalriskinsights.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/terrorist_attacks_in_western_europe_since_1970_n-557x1024.jpg&lt;/a>)
&lt;br>
&lt;br>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Boaz's Review of Books</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2016/02/17/boazs-review-of-books/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2016 22:22:16 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2016/02/17/boazs-review-of-books/</guid><description>&lt;p>A few books I recently finished reading are Ben Bernanke&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2015/10/25/books/review/ben-bernankes-the-courage-to-act.html">Courage to act&lt;/a>, Dr Philip Tetlock&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="http://www.economist.com/news/books-and-arts/21666098-forecasting-talent-luckily-it-can-be-learned-unclouded-vision">Superforecasting&lt;/a>, Peter Thiel’s &lt;a href="http://zerotoonebook.com/">Zero to One&lt;/a>, an unofficial biography on George Soros, and collection of druggie short stories titled &lt;a href="http://www.independent.co.uk/arts-entertainment/books/book-review-meeting-god-down-the-pub-the-acid-house-irvine-welsh-cape-pounds-999-1370403.html">Acid House&lt;/a> by Irvine Welsh. I do not expect to do justice to the arguments in the books (read a real book review if you want that), I&amp;rsquo;m just sharing the lessons I learned from them as a little exercise.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Superforecasting is a persuasive essay by a well known academic, Dr Philip Tetlock, on how hard it is to make good decisions. The first half sets the ground by arguing that most &amp;ldquo;expert&amp;rdquo; predictions are either wrong or too vague to assess. There is an entire cottage industry of pundits and hacks built upon the fact that human beings crave certainty and simple narratives in an increasingly uncertain world. Unlike the authors, I don’t think this industry will ever disappear: we’ve still got horoscopes in the internet age. Humans are attracted to anecdotal evidence like we are to junk food: it is appealing for evolutionary reasons, even if we know it shouldn’t be.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What I read in 2015</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2015/12/27/what-i-read-in-2015/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2015 22:22:16 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2015/12/27/what-i-read-in-2015/</guid><description>&lt;p>I bought my Kindle slightly over a year ago, and since it has accompanied me everywhere I&amp;rsquo;ve been.
It has provided me with entertainment on long journeys and education in subjects where I had none. I would like to share some of my favourite quotes. I have sorted them based on when I started reading them, with some slight editing.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="december-2014">December (2014)&lt;/h3>
&lt;h4 id="the-prince-niccolò-machiavelli">﻿The Prince (Niccolò Machiavelli)&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Besides, pretexts for taking away the property are never wanting; for he who has once begun to live by robbery will always find pretexts for seizing what belongs to others; but reasons for taking life, on the contrary, are more difficult to find and sooner lapse.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>