<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Crypto on Boaz Sobrado's Website</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/categories/crypto/</link><description>Recent content in Crypto on Boaz Sobrado's Website</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&amp;copy; 2024 &lt;a href="https://www.boazsobrado.com/">Boaz Sobrado&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 03:11:22 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://boazsobrado.com/categories/crypto/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Is 2024 the year Bitcoin obituaries died?</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2024/12/29/is-2024-the-year-bitcoin-obituaries-died/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 03:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2024/12/29/is-2024-the-year-bitcoin-obituaries-died/</guid><description>&lt;p>The chart tracks the frequency of &amp;ldquo;Bitcoin obituaries&amp;rdquo; - articles declaring Bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s demise - from 2010 to 2024.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The number of such articles peaked dramatically in 2017 with 124 publications, coinciding with Bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s first major price surge. Since then, obituaries have steadily declined, reaching just 2 articles in 2024 despite Bitcoin crossing $100,000.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This reduction in negative predictions, from the 2017 peak to present day, suggests a notable shift in how the cryptocurrency is perceived by commentators and institutions.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How Stripe And Stablecoins Are Rewiring Remote Work</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2024/12/17/how-stripe-and-stablecoins-are-rewiring-remote-work/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2024/12/17/how-stripe-and-stablecoins-are-rewiring-remote-work/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Originally published in &lt;a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/digital-assets/2024/12/17/how-stripe-and-stablecoins-are-rewiring-remote-work/">Forbes Digital Assets&lt;/a>. Author&amp;rsquo;s archive copy.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Every month, Maria would board a ferry in Buenos Aires for a one-and-a-half-hour journey to Colonia, Uruguay. The trip wasn&amp;rsquo;t for leisure. It was the only way she could receive payment for her work as a freelance contractor for European companies. Under Argentina&amp;rsquo;s strict capital controls, this arduous monthly pilgrimage was her lifeline to the global digital economy. &amp;ldquo;The whole day would be lost just to get paid,&amp;rdquo; says Maria (name changed for privacy). &amp;ldquo;It was exhausting, but we had no choice. The official systems just didn&amp;rsquo;t work for freelancers like me.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Crypto Banks Under Fire? Regulatory Crackdowns And Opportunities</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2024/10/20/crypto-banks-under-fire-regulatory-crackdowns-and-opportunities/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2024/10/20/crypto-banks-under-fire-regulatory-crackdowns-and-opportunities/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Originally published in &lt;a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/digital-assets/2024/10/20/crypto-banks-under-fire-regulatory-crackdowns-and-opportunities/">Forbes Digital Assets&lt;/a>. Author&amp;rsquo;s archive copy.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Two years after FTX&amp;rsquo;s implosion, financial regulators are still closely scrutinizing the cryptocurrency industry. In the United States, several targeted enforcement actions have been levied against crypto banks and companies, signaling an increased focus on compliance and risk management in the sector.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Following the collapse of Signature Bank and Silvergate, Pennsylvania-based Customers Bank has emerged as a key player in the crypto banking space, onboarding clients like Kraken and absorbing approximately $2 billion in deposits from crypto clients. A major draw for Customers Bank was its real-time payments system licensed from TassatPay, the same technology that had powered Signature Bank’s Signet. However, Customers Bank found itself under federal scrutiny, receiving an &lt;a href="https://www.federalreserve.gov/newsevents/pressreleases/enforcement20240808a.htm" title="https://www.federalreserve.gov/newsevents/pressreleases/enforcement20240808a.htm">enforcement action&lt;/a> from the Federal Reserve on August 5, 2024. The action cited “significant deficiencies” in the bank’s risk management practices and its compliance with anti-money laundering (AML) regulations, particularly in relation to its digital asset services.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Stablecoin Volumes Reach $450 Billion Monthly While Bitcoin Rises</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2024/09/28/stablecoin-volumes-reach-450-billion-monthly-while-bitcoin-rises/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2024/09/28/stablecoin-volumes-reach-450-billion-monthly-while-bitcoin-rises/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Originally published in &lt;a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/boazsobrado/2024/09/28/stablecoin-volumes-reach-450-billion-monthly-while-bitcoin-rises/">Forbes&lt;/a>. Author&amp;rsquo;s archive copy.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>People pass by a cryptocurrency exchange branch near the Grand Bazaar in Istanbul on October 20, &amp;hellip; [+] 2021, a day after Bitcoin took another step closer to mainstream investing with the launch of a new security on Wall Street tied to futures of the cryptocurrency. (Photo by Ozan KOSE / AFP) (Photo by OZAN KOSE/AFP via Getty Images)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>AFP via Getty Images&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Regardless of one’s opinion on Bitcoin &lt;a href="https://www.forbes.com/digital-assets/assets/bitcoin-btc/">Bitcoin&lt;/a> , it is now generally acknowledged that it is not a passing fad. Wall Street trades it, politicians appeal to its supporters, intergovernmental agencies examine it and regulators have begun to vigorously scrutinize the cryptocurrency industry it birthed. But Bitcoin’s adoption and success as a political movement, now largely taken for granted, has come with ideological compromises that some early supporters may eschew.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Crypto Should Disrupt Current Anti-Money Laundering Practices, Not Adopt Them</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2022/03/31/crypto-should-disrupt-current-anti-money-laundering-practices-not-adopt-them/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2022/03/31/crypto-should-disrupt-current-anti-money-laundering-practices-not-adopt-them/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Originally published in &lt;a href="https://www.coindesk.com/layer2/2022/03/31/crypto-should-disrupt-current-anti-money-laundering-practices-not-adopt-them/">CoinDesk&lt;/a>&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Until the early 20th century, highly respected doctors would routinely engage in bloodletting to cure ailments ranging from acne to tuberculosis. While we have left bloodletting behind, we are still engaging in putatively helpful, but veritably destructive practices.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Modern know-your-customer/anti-money laundering (KYC/AML) regulations are equivalent to financial bloodletting today: They do little good and may cause a lot of harm. Yet whether we like it or not, the KYC/AML nightmare is coming to crypto.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>GameFi’s Promise and Reality Are Still Worlds Apart</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2022/03/08/gamefis-promise-and-reality-are-still-worlds-apart/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2022/03/08/gamefis-promise-and-reality-are-still-worlds-apart/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Originally published in &lt;a href="https://www.coindesk.com/layer2/2022/03/08/gamefis-promise-and-reality-are-still-worlds-apart/">CoinDesk&lt;/a>&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Among crypto&amp;rsquo;s hottest trends is GameFi, which brings Web 3&amp;rsquo;s advantages to gaming. Web 3&amp;rsquo;s meaning &lt;a href="https://cobie.substack.com/p/wtf-is-web3">varies&lt;/a> by individual but reflects rising demand among people who are spending more time and money in meta worlds to own their virtual assets, free from the interference of platform developers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But are strong in-game property rights compatible with fun, escapist experiences that users are seeking?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Skeptics are not convinced. They say that GameFi games are not fun but rather merely repackaged versions of the worst elements of decentralized finance (&lt;a href="https://www.coindesk.com/learn/what-is-defi/">DeFi&lt;/a>). Play-to-earn games, some skeptics say, suffer because they are &lt;a href="https://frankmuci.substack.com/p/are-play-to-earn-p2e-games-pyramid?r=69dfl&amp;amp;utm_campaign=post&amp;amp;utm_medium=web">more or less pyramid&lt;/a> schemes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Are Crypto Investors Savvy or Suckers? The UK’s Tax and Financial Regulators Don’t Agree</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2022/02/24/are-crypto-investors-savvy-or-suckers-the-uks-tax-and-financial-regulators-dont-agree/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2022/02/24/are-crypto-investors-savvy-or-suckers-the-uks-tax-and-financial-regulators-dont-agree/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Originally published in &lt;a href="https://www.coindesk.com/layer2/2022/02/24/are-crypto-investors-savvy-or-suckers-the-uks-leading-tax-and-financial-regulators-dont-agree/">CoinDesk Magazine&lt;/a>&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Are crypto investors financially savvy investors who are capable of understanding the nuances of blockchain, Web 3 and &lt;a href="https://www.coindesk.com/learn/what-is-defi/">decentralized finance&lt;/a>? Or are they mostly vulnerable, uneducated speculators who are being taken advantage of?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.fca.org.uk/">The Financial Conduct Authority (FCA)&lt;/a>, the U.K.&amp;rsquo;s financial regulator, believes they are the latter, while the U.K.&amp;rsquo;s tax collection agency, &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/organisations/hm-revenue-customs">HM Revenue &amp;amp; Customs&lt;/a>, or HMRC, believes they are the former. While the agencies have issued a few helpful guidelines, their differing opinions underscore a fundamental inability to provide more sweeping and effective oversight that would protect consumers and ensure the industry&amp;rsquo;s development. Delays in finding such common ground are slowing progress on both fronts.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Quest for Perp AMMs</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2021/10/04/the-quest-for-perp-amms/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2021/10/04/the-quest-for-perp-amms/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Originally published in &lt;a href="https://www.wired.com/story/crypto-remittances-cuba/">Deribit Insights&lt;/a>. Co-authored with Dr. Abdulla Al-Kamil.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="what-are-perpetual-futures">What are perpetual futures?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Perpetual swaps (also known as perpetual futures or perps) are the most widely used derivative product in crypto. Perps are futures contracts with no expiration or settlement. Instead of expiring on a given day, a funding rate mechanism is used to tie the price to an index of the price of the underlying asset. The funding rate mechanism is simple, several times a day participants must pay each other based on the imbalance between mark price and index price:&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>