<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Forbes Commentary on Boaz Sobrado's Website</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/series/forbes-commentary/</link><description>Recent content in Forbes Commentary on Boaz Sobrado's Website</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&amp;copy; 2024 &lt;a href="https://www.boazsobrado.com/">Boaz Sobrado&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 17:38:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://boazsobrado.com/series/forbes-commentary/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What Bernie Sanders And Donald Trump Get Wrong About Credit Cards</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2024/12/22/what-bernie-sanders-and-donald-trump-get-wrong-about-credit-cards/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 17:38:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2024/12/22/what-bernie-sanders-and-donald-trump-get-wrong-about-credit-cards/</guid><description>&lt;p>In &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Code_of_Hammurabi" title="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Code_of_Hammurabi">Hammurabi&amp;rsquo;s ancient Babylon&lt;/a>, rulers were already worried about capping interest rates to protect borrowers from exploitation. Nearly 4,000 years later, we&amp;rsquo;re still debating the same questions about consumer credit—particularly when it comes to lending to underserved populations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Both Donald Trump and Bernie Sanders have recently proposed &lt;a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/bernie-sanders-elon-musk-very-smart-rfk-jr-is-right-2024-12" title="https://www.businessinsider.com/bernie-sanders-elon-musk-very-smart-rfk-jr-is-right-2024-12">capping credit card interest&lt;/a> rates at 10%: a rare moment of agreement between political opposites. While the intention to protect consumers is admirable, such proposals risk misdiagnosing the real problem.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How Digital Collateral Is Revolutionising Credit In Emerging Markets</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2024/12/22/how-digital-collateral-is-revolutionising-credit-in-emerging-markets/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2024/12/22/how-digital-collateral-is-revolutionising-credit-in-emerging-markets/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Originally published in &lt;a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/boazsobrado/2024/12/22/how-digital-collateral-is-revolutionizing-credit-in-emerging-markets/">Forbes&lt;/a>. Author&amp;rsquo;s archive copy.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a bustling workshop in Bogotá, Colombia, James Downer is busy assembling e-bikes. He is reimagining how to bring financial services to Latin America&amp;rsquo;s informal economy. His startup &lt;a href="https://www.guajirabikes.co/" title="https://www.guajirabikes.co">Guajira Bikes&lt;/a> manufactures e-bikes with a unique feature: they can be remotely disabled if payments are missed. These vehicles are sold to Venezuelan migrants and gig economy workers who lack traditional credit histories, enabling them to generate income through delivery services and other jobs.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How Stripe And Stablecoins Are Rewiring Remote Work</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2024/12/17/how-stripe-and-stablecoins-are-rewiring-remote-work/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2024/12/17/how-stripe-and-stablecoins-are-rewiring-remote-work/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Originally published in &lt;a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/digital-assets/2024/12/17/how-stripe-and-stablecoins-are-rewiring-remote-work/">Forbes Digital Assets&lt;/a>. Author&amp;rsquo;s archive copy.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Every month, Maria would board a ferry in Buenos Aires for a one-and-a-half-hour journey to Colonia, Uruguay. The trip wasn&amp;rsquo;t for leisure. It was the only way she could receive payment for her work as a freelance contractor for European companies. Under Argentina&amp;rsquo;s strict capital controls, this arduous monthly pilgrimage was her lifeline to the global digital economy. &amp;ldquo;The whole day would be lost just to get paid,&amp;rdquo; says Maria (name changed for privacy). &amp;ldquo;It was exhausting, but we had no choice. The official systems just didn&amp;rsquo;t work for freelancers like me.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Will Regulation Drive Consolidation For European Retail Brokers?</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2024/11/30/will-regulation-drive-consolidation-for-european-retail-brokers/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2024/11/30/will-regulation-drive-consolidation-for-european-retail-brokers/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Originally published in &lt;a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/boazsobrado/2024/11/30/will-regulation-drive-consolidation-for-european-retail-brokers/">Forbes&lt;/a>. Author&amp;rsquo;s archive copy.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Brookerchooser, an &lt;a href="https://brokerchooser.com/" title="https://brokerchooser.com/">online broker comparison site&lt;/a>, hosted a Fintech panel discussion in London last month where it became clear that the retail trading industry stands at a crossroads in Europe.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a discussion that included representatives from retail brokers such as &lt;a href="https://www.xtb.com/" title="https://www.xtb.com/">XTB&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://www.home.saxo/" title="https://www.home.saxo/">Saxo&lt;/a>, it was argued that as regulatory pressures mount and user acquisition costs soar, the sector appears poised to undergo a structural transformation similar to what we&amp;rsquo;ve witnessed in consumer credit markets.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Central Banks Are Increasingly Studying Bitcoin</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2024/10/27/central-banks-are-increasingly-studying-bitcoin/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2024/10/27/central-banks-are-increasingly-studying-bitcoin/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Originally published in &lt;a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/boazsobrado/2024/10/27/central-banks-are-increasingly-studying-bitcoin/">Forbes&lt;/a>. Author&amp;rsquo;s archive copy.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In recent years, a growing body of research has emerged from central banks and financial institutions, focusing on Bitcoin and its potential impact on monetary policy. These studies, issued by organizations such as the Minneapolis Federal Reserve, the European Central Bank (ECB), and the International Monetary Fund (IMF), highlight a key theme: the disruptive nature of Bitcoin and other cryptocurrencies could limit the ability of central banks to perform their traditional role in managing economies. Advocates have argued that Bitcoin could be an alternative to central banking, are central banks finally recognizing Bitcoin as a potential threat?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Crypto Banks Under Fire? Regulatory Crackdowns And Opportunities</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2024/10/20/crypto-banks-under-fire-regulatory-crackdowns-and-opportunities/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2024/10/20/crypto-banks-under-fire-regulatory-crackdowns-and-opportunities/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Originally published in &lt;a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/digital-assets/2024/10/20/crypto-banks-under-fire-regulatory-crackdowns-and-opportunities/">Forbes Digital Assets&lt;/a>. Author&amp;rsquo;s archive copy.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Two years after FTX&amp;rsquo;s implosion, financial regulators are still closely scrutinizing the cryptocurrency industry. In the United States, several targeted enforcement actions have been levied against crypto banks and companies, signaling an increased focus on compliance and risk management in the sector.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Following the collapse of Signature Bank and Silvergate, Pennsylvania-based Customers Bank has emerged as a key player in the crypto banking space, onboarding clients like Kraken and absorbing approximately $2 billion in deposits from crypto clients. A major draw for Customers Bank was its real-time payments system licensed from TassatPay, the same technology that had powered Signature Bank’s Signet. However, Customers Bank found itself under federal scrutiny, receiving an &lt;a href="https://www.federalreserve.gov/newsevents/pressreleases/enforcement20240808a.htm" title="https://www.federalreserve.gov/newsevents/pressreleases/enforcement20240808a.htm">enforcement action&lt;/a> from the Federal Reserve on August 5, 2024. The action cited “significant deficiencies” in the bank’s risk management practices and its compliance with anti-money laundering (AML) regulations, particularly in relation to its digital asset services.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Stablecoin Volumes Reach $450 Billion Monthly While Bitcoin Rises</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2024/09/28/stablecoin-volumes-reach-450-billion-monthly-while-bitcoin-rises/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2024/09/28/stablecoin-volumes-reach-450-billion-monthly-while-bitcoin-rises/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Originally published in &lt;a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/boazsobrado/2024/09/28/stablecoin-volumes-reach-450-billion-monthly-while-bitcoin-rises/">Forbes&lt;/a>. Author&amp;rsquo;s archive copy.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>People pass by a cryptocurrency exchange branch near the Grand Bazaar in Istanbul on October 20, &amp;hellip; [+] 2021, a day after Bitcoin took another step closer to mainstream investing with the launch of a new security on Wall Street tied to futures of the cryptocurrency. (Photo by Ozan KOSE / AFP) (Photo by OZAN KOSE/AFP via Getty Images)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>AFP via Getty Images&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Regardless of one’s opinion on Bitcoin &lt;a href="https://www.forbes.com/digital-assets/assets/bitcoin-btc/">Bitcoin&lt;/a> , it is now generally acknowledged that it is not a passing fad. Wall Street trades it, politicians appeal to its supporters, intergovernmental agencies examine it and regulators have begun to vigorously scrutinize the cryptocurrency industry it birthed. But Bitcoin’s adoption and success as a political movement, now largely taken for granted, has come with ideological compromises that some early supporters may eschew.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ads In Your Banking App? Why Fintechs Are Starting Ads Ventures</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2024/09/10/ads-in-your-banking-app-why-fintechs-are-starting-ads-ventures/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2024/09/10/ads-in-your-banking-app-why-fintechs-are-starting-ads-ventures/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Originally published in &lt;a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/boazsobrado/2024/09/10/ads-in-your-banking-app-why-fintechs-are-starting-ads-ventures/">Forbes&lt;/a>. Author&amp;rsquo;s archive copy.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fintech companies around the world are establishing new advertising ventures this year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Paypal launched &lt;a href="https://newsroom.paypal-corp.com/2024-09-05-Introducing-PayPal-Everywhere" title="https://newsroom.paypal-corp.com/2024-09-05-Introducing-PayPal-Everywhere">PayPal Everywhere&lt;/a> earlier in September, a product where users can collect rewards and use PayPal both in stores and online. Rewards and cashback are enticing to consumers, but the ability to individually target potential customers with offers and deals is attractive to advertisers. Back in May, PayPal announced that they had poached Uber’s Mark Grether to start its own advertising network. In advertising circles, Grether is known for helping jumpstart Uber’s advertising business and growing it into a behemoth that is set to make &lt;a href="https://www.adweek.com/commerce/uber-says-that-it-will-make-more-than-1-billion-in-ad-revenue-this-year/#:~:text=Uber%20Advertising%27s%20annual%20revenue%20runrevenue%20run%20rate%20last%20year." title="https://www.adweek.com/commerce/uber-says-that-it-will-make-more-than-1-billion-in-ad-revenue-this-year/#:~:text=Uber%20Advertising&amp;#39;s%20annual%20revenue%20runrevenue%20run%20rate%20last%20year.">1 billion dollars in revenue this year&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>