<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Crypto on Boaz Sobrado's Website</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/tags/crypto/</link><description>Recent content in Crypto on Boaz Sobrado's Website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&amp;copy; 2022 &lt;a href="https://www.boazsobrado.com/">Boaz Sobrado&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 13:11:22 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://boazsobrado.com/tags/crypto/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Decentralised Bitcoin trading platform BISQ has hit record highs.</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2024/04/01/decentralised-bitcoin-trading-platform-bisq-has-hit-record-highs./</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2024/04/01/decentralised-bitcoin-trading-platform-bisq-has-hit-record-highs./</guid><description>Last year I wrote about the problems peer-to-peer trading networks were facing. This quarter BISQ, a decentralised peer-to-peer network, has shattered all previous records.
This quarter was its highest dollar volume quarter, lead high BTC/XMR volume.
But fiat volumes are at all time highs too, with tremendous growth in the BRL and EUR pairs.
In terms of fiat payment methods, the rise of PIX in Brazil is worth pointing out.</description></item><item><title>A quick view at P2P trading volumes on BISQ</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2023/09/17/a-quick-view-at-p2p-trading-volumes-on-bisq/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2023/09/17/a-quick-view-at-p2p-trading-volumes-on-bisq/</guid><description>Originally published on X
Crypto newbies seem to forget that the original way to buy bitcoin was through peer-to-peer trading on sites like LocalBitcoins. At a time when the fall of FTX and the rise of blockchain surveillance companies like @chainalysis highlighted the risks of centralised exchanges, P2P markets have failed to capitalise on the opportunity. In fact, the P2P market has suffered a lot of changes recently, with the shutting down of @LocalBitcoins, the management turbulence around @raycivkit&amp;rsquo;s resignation at @paxful.</description></item><item><title>Crypto Critics Corner - An Argument for Tether in Cuba</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2022/09/01/crypto-critics-corner-an-argument-for-tether-in-cuba/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2022/09/01/crypto-critics-corner-an-argument-for-tether-in-cuba/</guid><description>I discuss the realities of the crypto markets with two of the most informed crypto skeptics.</description></item><item><title>Arise TV - Cross Border Payments</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2022/07/20/arise-tv-cross-border-payments/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2022/07/20/arise-tv-cross-border-payments/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Crypto Should Disrupt Current Anti-Money Laundering Practices, Not Adopt Them</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2022/03/31/crypto-should-disrupt-current-anti-money-laundering-practices-not-adopt-them/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2022/03/31/crypto-should-disrupt-current-anti-money-laundering-practices-not-adopt-them/</guid><description>Originally published in CoinDesk
Until the early 20th century, highly respected doctors would routinely engage in bloodletting to cure ailments ranging from acne to tuberculosis. While we have left bloodletting behind, we are still engaging in putatively helpful, but veritably destructive practices.
Modern know-your-customer/anti-money laundering (KYC/AML) regulations are equivalent to financial bloodletting today: They do little good and may cause a lot of harm. Yet whether we like it or not, the KYC/AML nightmare is coming to crypto.</description></item><item><title>GameFi’s Promise and Reality Are Still Worlds Apart</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2022/03/08/gamefis-promise-and-reality-are-still-worlds-apart/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2022/03/08/gamefis-promise-and-reality-are-still-worlds-apart/</guid><description>Originally published in CoinDesk
Among crypto&amp;rsquo;s hottest trends is GameFi, which brings Web 3&amp;rsquo;s advantages to gaming. Web 3&amp;rsquo;s meaning varies by individual but reflects rising demand among people who are spending more time and money in meta worlds to own their virtual assets, free from the interference of platform developers.
But are strong in-game property rights compatible with fun, escapist experiences that users are seeking?
Skeptics are not convinced. They say that GameFi games are not fun but rather merely repackaged versions of the worst elements of decentralized finance (DeFi).</description></item><item><title>Are Crypto Investors Savvy or Suckers? The UK’s Tax and Financial Regulators Don’t Agree</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2022/02/24/are-crypto-investors-savvy-or-suckers-the-uks-tax-and-financial-regulators-dont-agree/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2022/02/24/are-crypto-investors-savvy-or-suckers-the-uks-tax-and-financial-regulators-dont-agree/</guid><description>Originally published in CoinDesk Magazine
Are crypto investors financially savvy investors who are capable of understanding the nuances of blockchain, Web 3 and decentralized finance? Or are they mostly vulnerable, uneducated speculators who are being taken advantage of?
The Financial Conduct Authority (FCA), the U.K.&amp;rsquo;s financial regulator, believes they are the latter, while the U.K.&amp;rsquo;s tax collection agency, HM Revenue &amp;amp; Customs, or HMRC, believes they are the former. While the agencies have issued a few helpful guidelines, their differing opinions underscore a fundamental inability to provide more sweeping and effective oversight that would protect consumers and ensure the industry&amp;rsquo;s development.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin 2021 - What To Do When Your Country Bans Bitcoin</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2021/06/04/bitcoin-2021-what-to-do-when-your-country-bans-bitcoin/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2021/06/04/bitcoin-2021-what-to-do-when-your-country-bans-bitcoin/</guid><description>On Over-Compliance Full Version</description></item><item><title>On The Brink - On Bitcoin adoption trends in Cuba</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2021/06/04/on-the-brink-on-bitcoin-adoption-trends-in-cuba/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2021/06/04/on-the-brink-on-bitcoin-adoption-trends-in-cuba/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>