<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Credit on Boaz Sobrado's Website</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/tags/credit/</link><description>Recent content in Credit on Boaz Sobrado's Website</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&amp;copy; 2024 &lt;a href="https://www.boazsobrado.com/">Boaz Sobrado&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2023 13:11:22 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://boazsobrado.com/tags/credit/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Numbers Behind Small Loans</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2023/09/23/the-numbers-behind-small-loans/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2023 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2023/09/23/the-numbers-behind-small-loans/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Code of Hammurabi (c. 1700 B.C.E.) is one of the earliest known legal texts. It contains the first known formulation of &lt;em>lex talonis&lt;/em>, the principle of exact retaliation. Today people are most familiar with its Biblical version: &lt;em>an eye for an eye&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Code of Hammurabi is also the first known attempt of a regulator to cap lending interest rates:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>If a merchant lends grain at interest, for one gur he shall receive one hundred sila as interest (33 percent); if he lends money at interest, for one shekel of silver he shall receive one-fifth of a shekel as interest (20 percent).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Old Age Originations</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2023/07/16/old-age-originations/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2023/07/16/old-age-originations/</guid><description>&lt;p>In my &lt;a href="https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2023/06/17/from-subprime-crisis-to-the-newly-prime-crisis/">previous post&lt;/a> I discussed how credit score inflation contributed to the flurry of US mortgage originations in 2020-2021. As you can see from the chart below, the scale of the mortgage boom was truly unprecedented:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://boazsobrado.com/images/mortgage_origination_credit_score.png" alt="Mortgage origination by credit score">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another part of the story is the quantity of older people taking out mortgages, which was vastly higher than in any previous period. The rise of the 70+ cohort is particularly exceptional.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The vast majority of these mortgages will not be paid back by the original mortgage holder. The average mortgage term in the US is 30 years. Life expectancy at birth is 79 for women and 73 for men. Healthy men reaching 70 can expect to live till 85. Very few will make it to 100+.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>