<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Verbose Musings on Boaz Sobrado's Website</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/series/verbose-musings/</link><description>Recent content in Verbose Musings on Boaz Sobrado's Website</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&amp;copy; 2022 &lt;a href="https://www.boazsobrado.com/">Boaz Sobrado&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 13:11:22 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://boazsobrado.com/series/verbose-musings/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Social Proof of Work</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2021/01/15/social-proof-of-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2021/01/15/social-proof-of-work/</guid><description>On why many intellectual jobs are pretend jobs, why pretend work is actually a valid way of assessing real work, ponzi schemes and imposed structure.
Graduate recruiters &amp;amp; Team JUST When I arrived at Cambridge in 2011 I was immediately approached by hordes of corporates trying to sell me (a clueless teenager) a vision of what I should do after university. Law firms, investment banks and consultancies spend a large amount of money getting clueless students to go to career events.</description></item><item><title>Thirteen hours in Rotterdam</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2017/01/11/thirteen-hours-in-rotterdam/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2017 11:32:32 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2017/01/11/thirteen-hours-in-rotterdam/</guid><description>Oscar Wilde once wrote:
“Whenever a man does a thoroughly stupid thing, it is always from the noblest motives.”
I bought a bus ticket from London to Rotterdam. I did this in order to save what effectively amounts to the price of a handful of beers in London prices. I needed to get to Budapest, and I already had a flight leaving from Rotterdam booked. I spent 8 excruciating hours on a bus from London Victoria to Rotterdam Centraal, to in Rotterdam at 5 am in a cold winter morning.</description></item><item><title>Donald Trump and Zuckerberg's Matrix</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2016/02/29/donald-trump-and-zuckerbergs-matrix/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Feb 2016 22:22:16 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2016/02/29/donald-trump-and-zuckerbergs-matrix/</guid><description>Prediction markets have the Republican nomination for President of the USA going to billionaire reality TV host and megalomaniac Donald Trump. On the other side of the aisle, self-described socialist Sanders is making Hillary Clinton’s campaign sweat. This isn’t “politics as usual” for anyone except the writers of The Simpsons. According to the party decides theory (or at least my interpretation of Nate Silver’s interpretation) the party, as a loose coalition of opinion forming individuals, can heavily weigh in on who gets nominated.</description></item><item><title>Don't fear foreign education</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2012/11/20/dont-fear-foreign-education/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2012 15:52:58 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2012/11/20/dont-fear-foreign-education/</guid><description>Startling new data show that emigration out of Hungary is at a 20-year record high and that many more Hungarians have seriously considered leaving Hungary to live, work, or study in another member state of the EU. But instead of speaking ominously about the potentially catastrophic consequences of such emigration trends for Hungary, it is useful to think of this increased mobility as a potentially positive phenomenon.
Geographic mobility is often an indicator of social mobility.</description></item></channel></rss>