<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Coding on Boaz Sobrado's Website</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/tags/coding/</link><description>Recent content in Coding on Boaz Sobrado's Website</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&amp;copy; 2024 &lt;a href="https://www.boazsobrado.com/">Boaz Sobrado&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 13:11:22 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://boazsobrado.com/tags/coding/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Automating my business</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2019/08/12/automating-my-business/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2019/08/12/automating-my-business/</guid><description>&lt;p>As a small business owner keeping track of things can be surprisingly difficult: how you spend your money, who owes you money, who you owe money, what are your expenses, margins, operating costs&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you have multiple revenue streams from multiple platforms, you can quickly reach a point where you ignore basic things, like for example how much you are making exactly. Specially when you are focused on numerous other things as you try to scale your business. I am guilty of having neglected this in the past.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Where I was in 2018</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2019/01/13/where-i-was-in-2018/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 22:52:56 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2019/01/13/where-i-was-in-2018/</guid><description>&lt;p>I spent a lot of time this year on the road. I started 2018 on a tropical beach in the Phillipines and ended it in Lisbon, with a lot of trips in between. Given that I spent a good part of this year playing around with maps for my thesis, I thought it would be fun to use my Google Location Services data to animate my movement this year. Here is the result:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img alt="image" src="https://boazsobrado.com/images/2me2018.gif">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-did-i-make-this-animation">How did I make this animation?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>First, I download my Location History using &lt;a href="https://takeout.google.com/settings/takeout">Google Takeout&lt;/a>. Then, I extracted the relevant data from the resulting JSON file using this code in R:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Automating SMS &amp; email</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2018/11/08/automating-sms-email/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2018 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2018/11/08/automating-sms-email/</guid><description>&lt;p>I face the following problem: I get a lot of similarly formatted emails that require some sort of action that can in theory be easily automated. For example, I get Woocommerce order notifications that I want to forward selectively to my team via SMS.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It turns out there is no Gmail extension that will help you do that (or at least I didn&amp;rsquo;t find anything like it). A better programmer would alter the php code of the Woocommerce site to interact with the API of a service like &lt;a href="https://www.smsglobal.com/">SMSGLOBAL&lt;/a>. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t quite wrap my head around the php code, and it didn&amp;rsquo;t really solve the issue of the other types of emails I get that require relatively automation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cuba’s short term property rental market 2017-2018</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2018/08/11/cubas-short-term-property-rental-market-2017-2018/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2018 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2018/08/11/cubas-short-term-property-rental-market-2017-2018/</guid><description>&lt;p>In July of 2017 President Trump announced with much fanfare a &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/av/world-us-canada-42345919/what-s-changed-in-us-cuba-relations-under-trump">new policy towards Cuba&lt;/a>. This was following the Obama administrations &amp;ldquo;thaw&amp;rdquo; in Cuban-American bilateral relations, which had lead to a noticable rise in Americas visiting the island. Then more bad news for the Cuban tourism industry:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Havana_syndrome">sonic warfare in the news&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.9news.com.au/world/2019/01/29/05/49/cuba-hurricane-three-dead-eastern-havana">hurricanes&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>All of this together had a noticable impact on the Cuban tourism sector. &lt;a href="http://www.escambray.cu/2018/cuba-mira-con-fuerza-a-los-cinco-millones-de-visitantes-extranjeros-en-2019/">Official Cuban statistics&lt;/a> show that tourism numbers are going up. This year there were a record number of visits. However, the truth is much more nuanced. Tourists &lt;em>flying&lt;/em> in to Cuba actually decreased by 6 percent. There was a strong rise in cruise ship passengers (48%), however the methodology of counting each disembarcation of a passenger as an extra visit might inflate tourism numbers. Moreover, cruise ship passengers spend less, particularly on acccommodation (they sleep on the boat).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How I made this website - tutorial</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2016/04/20/how-i-made-this-website-tutorial/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 14:12:49 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2016/04/20/how-i-made-this-website-tutorial/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="theory">Theory&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>As our activities are increasingly organised online – from business through voting to leisure time – knowing how to write (or even just understand) code is an increasingly coveted skill. Its benefits range wide; if you can code you will get a better job, improve your analytical skills, make work processes easier and cheaper.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These reasons led us – Dora and Boaz, authors of this article – to set up our websites as a means of learning and practising a bit of coding. We used amazing open source projects and their online tutorials as guidance, however, we have found that these tutorials are usually not written for people with no previous background in any sort of coding/hacking. Consequently, we have decided to write a tutorial in simple English in the hope that it will make it easier for you to set up your own website and really understand the logic behind each step.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using Google Maps API: Mol Bubi Competition</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2015/11/05/using-google-maps-api-mol-bubi-competition/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2015 11:36:16 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2015/11/05/using-google-maps-api-mol-bubi-competition/</guid><description>&lt;p>A few friends and I are involved in the Budapest public bicycle data science &lt;a href="https://dms.sztaki.hu/bubi/#/app/home">competition&lt;/a>. As of right now we are in the top ten, although in all honesty, it hasn&amp;rsquo;t really started yet.
We signed a non-disclosure agreement, so I cannot really share any cool details. What I can share however, is the function I wrote in R to get calculate the distances and duration of bike trips using Google Maps&amp;rsquo; &lt;a href="https://developers.google.com/maps/?hl=en">API&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>#distance calucations
#### This script uses RCurl and RJSONIO to download data from Google's API

library(RCurl)
library(RJSONIO)

#define api key as: api&amp;lt;-&amp;quot;YOURAPI&amp;quot;
#the function assumes address input in following dataframe:
#lat1,lng1,lat2,lng2

DistDur &amp;lt;- function(address,time = as.integer(Sys.time()),mode, return.call = &amp;quot;json&amp;quot;, sensor = &amp;quot;false&amp;quot;) {
 address1&amp;lt;-paste(address[,1],address[,2], sep=&amp;quot; &amp;quot;)
 address2&amp;lt;-paste(address[,3],address[,4], sep=&amp;quot; &amp;quot;)
 root &amp;lt;- &amp;quot;https://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/directions/&amp;quot;
 u &amp;lt;- paste(root, return.call, &amp;quot;?origin=&amp;quot;, address1, &amp;quot;&amp;amp;destination=&amp;quot;,address2,&amp;quot;&amp;amp;departure_time=&amp;quot;,time,&amp;quot;&amp;amp;mode=&amp;quot;,mode,&amp;quot;&amp;amp;key=&amp;quot;,api,sep = &amp;quot;&amp;quot;)
 for (a in 1:length(u)){
 url&amp;lt;-URLencode(u[a])
 doc &amp;lt;- getURL(url)
 x &amp;lt;- fromJSON(doc,simplify = FALSE)
 dist&amp;lt;-0
 dura&amp;lt;-0
 for (i in 1:length(x$routes[[1]]$legs[[1]]$steps))
 {
 dist&amp;lt;-x$routes[[1]]$legs[[1]]$steps[[i]]$distance$value+dist
 dura&amp;lt;-x$routes[[1]]$legs[[1]]$steps[[i]]$duration$value+dura
 }
 address$dura[a]&amp;lt;-dura
 address$dist[a]&amp;lt;-dist
 }
 return(address)
}
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>The code itself is quite simple, but its my first time using the Google Maps API and I was amazed by how easy it was. This and more can be found on my &lt;a href="www.github.com/sobradob">Github&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>