<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Advertising on Boaz Sobrado's Website</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/tags/advertising/</link><description>Recent content in Advertising on Boaz Sobrado's Website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&amp;copy; 2022 &lt;a href="https://www.boazsobrado.com/">Boaz Sobrado&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2024 13:11:22 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://boazsobrado.com/tags/advertising/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Can payments networks solve the online ad attribution problem?</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2024/03/31/can-payments-networks-solve-the-online-ad-attribution-problem/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2024 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2024/03/31/can-payments-networks-solve-the-online-ad-attribution-problem/</guid><description>I really enjoyed this Mobile Dev Memo podcast where Eric &amp;amp; Rishabh discuss the upcoming third party cookie depreciation and its consequences.
Winners of this new world will be the “walled compounds” of Facebook, Amazon and other major players. In other words, platforms that have a lot of first party data. Losers will be small publishers that lack it. The traffic of these small publishers will become significantly less valuable given with the loss of third party cookies.</description></item><item><title>My thoughts on Cambridge Analytica</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2020/11/07/my-thoughts-on-cambridge-analytica/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Nov 2020 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2020/11/07/my-thoughts-on-cambridge-analytica/</guid><description>I am writing this to share my conclusions regarding the Cambridge Analytica affair. I have a somewhat unique perspective on the topic for three reasons:
My day job consists of measuring the effectiveness of digital advertising. I have first hand experience with the technology and methods that Cambridge Analytica claims to have used. I played a small role in unearthing the Cambridge Analytica scandal. What Cambridge Analytica supposedly did The New Statesmen&amp;rsquo;s Laurie Clarke puts it in the following way:</description></item></channel></rss>