<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Financial Innovation on Boaz Sobrado's Website</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/tags/financial-innovation/</link><description>Recent content in Financial Innovation on Boaz Sobrado's Website</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&amp;copy; 2024 &lt;a href="https://www.boazsobrado.com/">Boaz Sobrado&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://boazsobrado.com/tags/financial-innovation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How Digital Collateral Is Revolutionising Credit In Emerging Markets</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2024/12/22/how-digital-collateral-is-revolutionising-credit-in-emerging-markets/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2024/12/22/how-digital-collateral-is-revolutionising-credit-in-emerging-markets/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Originally published in &lt;a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/boazsobrado/2024/12/22/how-digital-collateral-is-revolutionizing-credit-in-emerging-markets/">Forbes&lt;/a>. Author&amp;rsquo;s archive copy.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a bustling workshop in Bogotá, Colombia, James Downer is busy assembling e-bikes. He is reimagining how to bring financial services to Latin America&amp;rsquo;s informal economy. His startup &lt;a href="https://www.guajirabikes.co/" title="https://www.guajirabikes.co">Guajira Bikes&lt;/a> manufactures e-bikes with a unique feature: they can be remotely disabled if payments are missed. These vehicles are sold to Venezuelan migrants and gig economy workers who lack traditional credit histories, enabling them to generate income through delivery services and other jobs.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How Stripe And Stablecoins Are Rewiring Remote Work</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2024/12/17/how-stripe-and-stablecoins-are-rewiring-remote-work/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2024/12/17/how-stripe-and-stablecoins-are-rewiring-remote-work/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Originally published in &lt;a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/digital-assets/2024/12/17/how-stripe-and-stablecoins-are-rewiring-remote-work/">Forbes Digital Assets&lt;/a>. Author&amp;rsquo;s archive copy.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Every month, Maria would board a ferry in Buenos Aires for a one-and-a-half-hour journey to Colonia, Uruguay. The trip wasn&amp;rsquo;t for leisure. It was the only way she could receive payment for her work as a freelance contractor for European companies. Under Argentina&amp;rsquo;s strict capital controls, this arduous monthly pilgrimage was her lifeline to the global digital economy. &amp;ldquo;The whole day would be lost just to get paid,&amp;rdquo; says Maria (name changed for privacy). &amp;ldquo;It was exhausting, but we had no choice. The official systems just didn&amp;rsquo;t work for freelancers like me.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Central Banks Are Increasingly Studying Bitcoin</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2024/10/27/central-banks-are-increasingly-studying-bitcoin/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2024/10/27/central-banks-are-increasingly-studying-bitcoin/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Originally published in &lt;a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/boazsobrado/2024/10/27/central-banks-are-increasingly-studying-bitcoin/">Forbes&lt;/a>. Author&amp;rsquo;s archive copy.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In recent years, a growing body of research has emerged from central banks and financial institutions, focusing on Bitcoin and its potential impact on monetary policy. These studies, issued by organizations such as the Minneapolis Federal Reserve, the European Central Bank (ECB), and the International Monetary Fund (IMF), highlight a key theme: the disruptive nature of Bitcoin and other cryptocurrencies could limit the ability of central banks to perform their traditional role in managing economies. Advocates have argued that Bitcoin could be an alternative to central banking, are central banks finally recognizing Bitcoin as a potential threat?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Crypto Banks Under Fire? Regulatory Crackdowns And Opportunities</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2024/10/20/crypto-banks-under-fire-regulatory-crackdowns-and-opportunities/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2024/10/20/crypto-banks-under-fire-regulatory-crackdowns-and-opportunities/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Originally published in &lt;a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/digital-assets/2024/10/20/crypto-banks-under-fire-regulatory-crackdowns-and-opportunities/">Forbes Digital Assets&lt;/a>. Author&amp;rsquo;s archive copy.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Two years after FTX&amp;rsquo;s implosion, financial regulators are still closely scrutinizing the cryptocurrency industry. In the United States, several targeted enforcement actions have been levied against crypto banks and companies, signaling an increased focus on compliance and risk management in the sector.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Following the collapse of Signature Bank and Silvergate, Pennsylvania-based Customers Bank has emerged as a key player in the crypto banking space, onboarding clients like Kraken and absorbing approximately $2 billion in deposits from crypto clients. A major draw for Customers Bank was its real-time payments system licensed from TassatPay, the same technology that had powered Signature Bank’s Signet. However, Customers Bank found itself under federal scrutiny, receiving an &lt;a href="https://www.federalreserve.gov/newsevents/pressreleases/enforcement20240808a.htm" title="https://www.federalreserve.gov/newsevents/pressreleases/enforcement20240808a.htm">enforcement action&lt;/a> from the Federal Reserve on August 5, 2024. The action cited “significant deficiencies” in the bank’s risk management practices and its compliance with anti-money laundering (AML) regulations, particularly in relation to its digital asset services.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>