<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Financial Regulation on Boaz Sobrado's Website</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/categories/financial-regulation/</link><description>Recent content in Financial Regulation on Boaz Sobrado's Website</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&amp;copy; 2024 &lt;a href="https://www.boazsobrado.com/">Boaz Sobrado&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://boazsobrado.com/categories/financial-regulation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Crypto Banks Under Fire? Regulatory Crackdowns And Opportunities</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2024/10/20/crypto-banks-under-fire-regulatory-crackdowns-and-opportunities/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2024/10/20/crypto-banks-under-fire-regulatory-crackdowns-and-opportunities/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Originally published in &lt;a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/digital-assets/2024/10/20/crypto-banks-under-fire-regulatory-crackdowns-and-opportunities/">Forbes Digital Assets&lt;/a>. Author&amp;rsquo;s archive copy.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Two years after FTX&amp;rsquo;s implosion, financial regulators are still closely scrutinizing the cryptocurrency industry. In the United States, several targeted enforcement actions have been levied against crypto banks and companies, signaling an increased focus on compliance and risk management in the sector.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Following the collapse of Signature Bank and Silvergate, Pennsylvania-based Customers Bank has emerged as a key player in the crypto banking space, onboarding clients like Kraken and absorbing approximately $2 billion in deposits from crypto clients. A major draw for Customers Bank was its real-time payments system licensed from TassatPay, the same technology that had powered Signature Bank’s Signet. However, Customers Bank found itself under federal scrutiny, receiving an &lt;a href="https://www.federalreserve.gov/newsevents/pressreleases/enforcement20240808a.htm" title="https://www.federalreserve.gov/newsevents/pressreleases/enforcement20240808a.htm">enforcement action&lt;/a> from the Federal Reserve on August 5, 2024. The action cited “significant deficiencies” in the bank’s risk management practices and its compliance with anti-money laundering (AML) regulations, particularly in relation to its digital asset services.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>