<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Statistics on Boaz Sobrado's Website</title><link>https://sobradob.github.io/personal_site_2022/series/statistics/</link><description>Recent content in Statistics on Boaz Sobrado's Website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&amp;copy; 2022 &lt;a href="https://www.boazsobrado.com/">Boaz Sobrado&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 15:52:58 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sobradob.github.io/personal_site_2022/series/statistics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Leaflet timeline in R</title><link>https://sobradob.github.io/personal_site_2022/blog/2018/02/08/leaflet-timeline-in-r/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 15:52:58 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://sobradob.github.io/personal_site_2022/blog/2018/02/08/leaflet-timeline-in-r/</guid><description>Leaflet is a powerful tool for visualasing spatial data in R. However, after much googling I could not find an easy way to create a timeline to visualise changes in time. Therefore, I decided to create a simple shiny app that does it.
Raw Android GPS Movements Code The code below takes raw location measurements from my Android phone visualises them over time. The size of the circle is the confidence interval of the measurement. Before you go and try to find me at those spots, I no longer live there!</description></item><item><title>Time Series analysis for Facebook message volume</title><link>https://sobradob.github.io/personal_site_2022/blog/2017/12/01/time-series-analysis-for-facebook-message-volume/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 15:52:58 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://sobradob.github.io/personal_site_2022/blog/2017/12/01/time-series-analysis-for-facebook-message-volume/</guid><description>Introduction to the data set
The data is the amount of Facebook messages a user (me) sent and received between 2011 and 2016. The data was exported from Facebook, converted from HTML to JSON and subsequently read into R. For more details on how this was done, please consult here.
The original data source contains 413,101 timestamps and messages between 2008 and 2016. The volume of messages is very low between 2008-2011, and highly atypical to the rest of the series, so it was not considered in the sample.</description></item><item><title>Implementing a Kalman filter in R for Android GPS measurements</title><link>https://sobradob.github.io/personal_site_2022/blog/2017/08/29/implementing-a-kalman-filter-in-r-for-android-gps-measurements/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2017 17:58:21 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://sobradob.github.io/personal_site_2022/blog/2017/08/29/implementing-a-kalman-filter-in-r-for-android-gps-measurements/</guid><description>The problem I downloaded my data from Google Take-Out and have been playing around with it for my thesis. This is roughly what the data looks like after some pre-processing:
lon lat accuracy 5.115447 52.10574 877 5.115447 52.10574 877 5.113952 52.10451 18 5.115447 52.10574 877 5.115447 52.10574 877 5.115447 52.10574 877 As soon as I looked into it I realised there were some issues with the measurements. They were all over the place!
The circles are the measurements (with their radius representing the accuracy and the center being the point) and lines connect these measurements in time.</description></item><item><title>Bayesian Images</title><link>https://sobradob.github.io/personal_site_2022/blog/2017/05/22/bayesian-images/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 22:22:16 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://sobradob.github.io/personal_site_2022/blog/2017/05/22/bayesian-images/</guid><description>Graphs to accompany my poster presentation.
The data set The generated data is plotted below: Metropolis Hastings Algorithm This visual explanation of the Metropolis Hastings algorithm shows the proposal and the true density along with the Metropolis Hastings step. It was inspired and adapted from code by Balazs Torok.
Diagnostic Plots for Beta 2 via Gibbs Sampler Autocorrelation Plot The autocorrelations are negligable, suggesting good mixing.
Running Means Plot The running means have settled.
Three chain trace plot All three chains seem to be in the same place.</description></item></channel></rss>