<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog on Boaz Sobrado's Website</title><link>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blog on Boaz Sobrado's Website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&amp;copy; 2022 &lt;a href="https://www.boazsobrado.com/">Boaz Sobrado&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2023 13:11:22 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sobradob.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Mixpanel Live - Growth and Analytics</title><link>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2023/01/27/mixpanel-live-growth-and-analytics/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2023 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2023/01/27/mixpanel-live-growth-and-analytics/</guid><description>Link here should it not load below.</description></item><item><title>Films watched in 2022</title><link>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2023/01/01/films-watched-in-2022/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2023/01/01/films-watched-in-2022/</guid><description>Satantango A seven hour long Hungarian film marathon by Béla Tarr.
This film is shown surprisingly often in London, usually with two intermissions.
The Queen of Spades A quaint oldie film, fairly well done.
The Room Watching this was a lot of fun. Big cult following at the cinema, the audience was shouting out every line. You get spoons when stepping in as well.
Jackie Brown A Tartantino classic. Some say its his best, but apparently if you say this to Quentin&amp;rsquo;s face he&amp;rsquo;ll get angry at you.</description></item><item><title>Crypto Critics Corner - An Argument for Tether in Cuba</title><link>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2022/09/01/crypto-critics-corner-an-argument-for-tether-in-cuba/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2022/09/01/crypto-critics-corner-an-argument-for-tether-in-cuba/</guid><description>I discuss the realities of the crypto markets with two of the most informed crypto skeptics.</description></item><item><title>Arise TV - Cross Border Payments</title><link>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2022/07/20/arise-tv-cross-border-payments/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2022/07/20/arise-tv-cross-border-payments/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Crypto Should Disrupt Current Anti-Money Laundering Practices, Not Adopt Them</title><link>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2022/03/31/crypto-should-disrupt-current-anti-money-laundering-practices-not-adopt-them/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2022/03/31/crypto-should-disrupt-current-anti-money-laundering-practices-not-adopt-them/</guid><description>Originally published in CoinDesk
Until the early 20th century, highly respected doctors would routinely engage in bloodletting to cure ailments ranging from acne to tuberculosis. While we have left bloodletting behind, we are still engaging in putatively helpful, but veritably destructive practices.
Modern know-your-customer/anti-money laundering (KYC/AML) regulations are equivalent to financial bloodletting today: They do little good and may cause a lot of harm. Yet whether we like it or not, the KYC/AML nightmare is coming to crypto.</description></item><item><title>GameFi’s Promise and Reality Are Still Worlds Apart</title><link>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2022/03/08/gamefis-promise-and-reality-are-still-worlds-apart/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2022/03/08/gamefis-promise-and-reality-are-still-worlds-apart/</guid><description>Originally published in CoinDesk
Among crypto&amp;rsquo;s hottest trends is GameFi, which brings Web 3&amp;rsquo;s advantages to gaming. Web 3&amp;rsquo;s meaning varies by individual but reflects rising demand among people who are spending more time and money in meta worlds to own their virtual assets, free from the interference of platform developers.
But are strong in-game property rights compatible with fun, escapist experiences that users are seeking?
Skeptics are not convinced. They say that GameFi games are not fun but rather merely repackaged versions of the worst elements of decentralized finance (DeFi).</description></item><item><title>Are Crypto Investors Savvy or Suckers? The UK’s Tax and Financial Regulators Don’t Agree</title><link>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2022/02/24/are-crypto-investors-savvy-or-suckers-the-uks-tax-and-financial-regulators-dont-agree/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2022/02/24/are-crypto-investors-savvy-or-suckers-the-uks-tax-and-financial-regulators-dont-agree/</guid><description>Originally published in CoinDesk Magazine
Are crypto investors financially savvy investors who are capable of understanding the nuances of blockchain, Web 3 and decentralized finance? Or are they mostly vulnerable, uneducated speculators who are being taken advantage of?
The Financial Conduct Authority (FCA), the U.K.&amp;rsquo;s financial regulator, believes they are the latter, while the U.K.&amp;rsquo;s tax collection agency, HM Revenue &amp;amp; Customs, or HMRC, believes they are the former. While the agencies have issued a few helpful guidelines, their differing opinions underscore a fundamental inability to provide more sweeping and effective oversight that would protect consumers and ensure the industry&amp;rsquo;s development.</description></item><item><title>We All Need to Stop Only Seeing the Dark Side of Crypto</title><link>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2021/12/19/we-all-need-to-stop-only-seeing-the-dark-side-of-crypto/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2021 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2021/12/19/we-all-need-to-stop-only-seeing-the-dark-side-of-crypto/</guid><description>Originally published in Wired Magazine
IN 2021, BITCOIN went mainstream. Wall Street set its eyes on the world of crypto, with hotshot investors like hedge funder Paul Tudor Jones leading the pack; The Economist went from calling the cryptocurrency &amp;ldquo;useless&amp;rdquo; in 2018 to arguing that it belongs in most portfolios; tech CEOs Jack Dorsey and Elon Musk gamely crossed swords about Bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s merits at a conference run by an asset management firm. Popular opinion lags a bit: Many people still believe cryptocurrency is a giant, global get-rich-quick scheme.</description></item><item><title>The Quest for Perp AMMs</title><link>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2021/10/04/the-quest-for-perp-amms/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2021/10/04/the-quest-for-perp-amms/</guid><description>Originally published in Deribit Insights. Co-authored with Dr. Abdulla Al-Kamil.
What are perpetual futures? Perpetual swaps (also known as perpetual futures or perps) are the most widely used derivative product in crypto. Perps are futures contracts with no expiration or settlement. Instead of expiring on a given day, a funding rate mechanism is used to tie the price to an index of the price of the underlying asset. The funding rate mechanism is simple, several times a day participants must pay each other based on the imbalance between mark price and index price:</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin 2021 - What To Do When Your Country Bans Bitcoin</title><link>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2021/06/04/bitcoin-2021-what-to-do-when-your-country-bans-bitcoin/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2021/06/04/bitcoin-2021-what-to-do-when-your-country-bans-bitcoin/</guid><description>On Over-Compliance Full Version</description></item><item><title>On The Brink - On Bitcoin adoption trends in Cuba</title><link>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2021/06/04/on-the-brink-on-bitcoin-adoption-trends-in-cuba/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2021/06/04/on-the-brink-on-bitcoin-adoption-trends-in-cuba/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Disrupting ransom payments</title><link>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2021/01/15/disrupting-ransom-payments/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2021/01/15/disrupting-ransom-payments/</guid><description>Published on CoinDesk
What do the smart watch maker Garmin, the Isreali insurer Shirbit, the electronics manufacturer Foxconn, Delaware county in Pennsylvania, the foreign exchange company Travelex, the alcohol producer Campari and the Baltimore Public School system have in common?
They were all hit by ransomware attacks this year.
Ransomware attacks are when hackers gain access to the computer systems of the victim, and threaten to expose them or render them useless unless the victim pays a ransom.</description></item><item><title>Social Proof of Work</title><link>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2021/01/15/social-proof-of-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2021/01/15/social-proof-of-work/</guid><description>On why many intellectual jobs are pretend jobs, why pretend work is actually a valid way of assessing real work, ponzi schemes and imposed structure.
Graduate recruiters &amp;amp; Team JUST When I arrived at Cambridge in 2011 I was immediately approached by hordes of corporates trying to sell me (a clueless teenager) a vision of what I should do after university. Law firms, investment banks and consultancies spend a large amount of money getting clueless students to go to career events.</description></item><item><title>Ugocsa Non Coronat - the Visegradation of the European Union</title><link>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2021/01/01/ugocsa-non-coronat-the-visegradation-of-the-european-union/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2021/01/01/ugocsa-non-coronat-the-visegradation-of-the-european-union/</guid><description>There is an apocryphal story about a meeting of the representatives of Hungarian noblemen in 1527. These representatives had gathered to elect the new king Hungary, Ferdinand I, in a time of national crisis. The Ottoman empire had won a key battle at Mohacs and was threatening to conquer all of Hungary. Each nobleman a their vote for the new Habsburg king, until the representative of the smallest county in Hungary, Ugocsa (now in Ukraine) awaited his turn to raise his voice and say:</description></item><item><title>DeFi needs a Silk Road moment</title><link>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2020/12/11/defi-needs-a-silk-road-moment/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2020/12/11/defi-needs-a-silk-road-moment/</guid><description>This article was originally published as an Op-Ed on CoinDesk
Mainstream criminal adoption would prove that decentralized finance (DeFi) is building tools with real utility, because if there&amp;rsquo;s any one group that is both underserved in their access to sophisticated financial products and willing to pay huge premiums to acquire them, it&amp;rsquo;s criminals. The Silk Road was launched in February of 2011 and quickly became the first example of Bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s product-market fit. While some proponents of cryptocurrencies argue that today criminal activities are a small percentage of all cryptocurrency transactions, censorship resistance is one of the key features of all decentralized technologies and criminals have played a part in crypto&amp;rsquo;s wider adoption.</description></item><item><title>Why Cuba is primed for bitcoin adoption</title><link>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2020/12/11/why-cuba-is-primed-for-bitcoin-adoption/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2020/12/11/why-cuba-is-primed-for-bitcoin-adoption/</guid><description>This article was originally published as an Op-Ed on Decrypt
Cuba is having one of its worst years in recent memory&amp;mdash;but, as a consequence, a perfect storm is brewing on the island nation with regard to Bitcoin adoption.
Cubans live under a high level of financial censorship, as well as rampant inflation. Meanwhile, their access to foreign currencies has been heavily curtailed this year due to COVID and US sanctions. This has increased the appeal of cryptocurrencies, many of which act as censorship-resistant stores of value.</description></item><item><title>My thoughts on Cambridge Analytica</title><link>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2020/11/07/my-thoughts-on-cambridge-analytica/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Nov 2020 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2020/11/07/my-thoughts-on-cambridge-analytica/</guid><description>I am writing this to share my conclusions regarding the Cambridge Analytica affair. I have a somewhat unique perspective on the topic for three reasons:
My day job consists of measuring the effectiveness of digital advertising. I have first hand experience with the technology and methods that Cambridge Analytica claims to have used. I played a small role in unearthing the Cambridge Analytica scandal. What Cambridge Analytica supposedly did The New Statesmen&amp;rsquo;s Laurie Clarke puts it in the following way:</description></item><item><title>A day using money in Cuba</title><link>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2020/05/22/a-day-using-money-in-cuba/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2020/05/22/a-day-using-money-in-cuba/</guid><description>Ira wakes up craving some eggs for breakfast. She walks under the strong Cuban sun and visits the food market . She&amp;rsquo;s lucky: they have eggs today.
&amp;ldquo;How much for the box?&amp;rdquo; she asks, pointing at the box of 30 eggs.
&amp;ldquo;Four pesos&amp;rdquo;
She looks in her purse and finds a 100 peso note. She hands the note to the seller, who nods and hands her the eggs. She leaves without getting any change, nor did she expect to.</description></item><item><title>Restarting your sales after a coronavirus lockdown</title><link>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2020/04/20/restarting-your-sales-after-a-coronavirus-lockdown/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2020/04/20/restarting-your-sales-after-a-coronavirus-lockdown/</guid><description>As I write this, a novel strain of coronavirus (colloquially known as the rona) has a global lockdown. Unemployment rates are skyrocketing, the stock market has dropped substantially, but not nearly as much as consumer sentiment. Millions of businesses around the world, from small businesses like nail salons to tech giants like Airbnb are now facing the same problem: no revenues. At this point, we can only guess how long lockdowns will last. But there are encouraging signs that governments have decided to open.</description></item><item><title>Automating my business</title><link>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2019/08/12/automating-my-business/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2019/08/12/automating-my-business/</guid><description>As a small business owner keeping track of things can be surprisingly difficult: how you spend your money, who owes you money, who you owe money, what are your expenses, margins, operating costs&amp;hellip;
If you have multiple revenue streams from multiple platforms, you can quickly reach a point where you ignore basic things, like for example how much you are making exactly. Specially when you are focused on numerous other things as you try to scale your business.</description></item><item><title>Where I was in 2018</title><link>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2019/01/13/where-i-was-in-2018/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 22:52:56 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2019/01/13/where-i-was-in-2018/</guid><description>I spent a lot of time this year on the road. I started 2018 on a tropical beach in the Phillipines and ended it in Lisbon, with a lot of trips in between. Given that I spent a good part of this year playing around with maps for my thesis, I thought it would be fun to use my Google Location Services data to animate my movement this year. Here is the result:
How did I make this animation?</description></item><item><title>Automating SMS &amp; email</title><link>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2018/11/08/automating-sms-email/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2018 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2018/11/08/automating-sms-email/</guid><description>I face the following problem: I get a lot of similarly formatted emails that require some sort of action that can in theory be easily automated. For example, I get Woocommerce order notifications that I want to forward selectively to my team via SMS.
It turns out there is no Gmail extension that will help you do that (or at least I didn&amp;rsquo;t find anything like it). A better programmer would alter the php code of the Woocommerce site to interact with the API of a service like SMSGLOBAL.</description></item><item><title>Tale of two Johns</title><link>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2018/09/02/tale-of-two-johns/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2018 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2018/09/02/tale-of-two-johns/</guid><description>There has recently been a flurry of articles with a nice soundbite recycled from 2015. The title of the Observer&amp;rsquo;s version of the article is:
Men Named John Outnumber All Women in Most American Industries.
The New York Times writes:
Fewer Republican senators are women than men named John &amp;mdash; despite the fact that Johns represent 3.3 percent of the male population, while women represent 50.8 percent of the total population. Fewer Democratic governors are women than men named John.</description></item><item><title>Cuba’s short term property rental market 2017-2018</title><link>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2018/08/11/cubas-short-term-property-rental-market-2017-2018/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2018 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2018/08/11/cubas-short-term-property-rental-market-2017-2018/</guid><description>In July of 2017 President Trump announced with much fanfare a new policy towards Cuba. This was following the Obama administrations &amp;ldquo;thaw&amp;rdquo; in Cuban-American bilateral relations, which had lead to a noticable rise in Americas visiting the island. Then more bad news for the Cuban tourism industry:
sonic warfare in the news hurricanes All of this together had a noticable impact on the Cuban tourism sector. Official Cuban statistics show that tourism numbers are going up.</description></item><item><title>How to generate a Bitcoin vanity address using a Mac</title><link>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2018/08/11/how-to-generate-a-bitcoin-vanity-address-using-a-mac/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2018 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2018/08/11/how-to-generate-a-bitcoin-vanity-address-using-a-mac/</guid><description>A bitcoin vanity address is an address that starts in a particular way. Here is an example:
Once I saw these addresses exist, I obviously wanted one. There are many websites that help you generate a vanity address, however it involves a trusted third party. Nick Szabo doesn&amp;rsquo;t like trusted third parties.
There are clear, up to date instructions on how to do this on Windows. The only thing I found on Mac was this blogpost from 2013.</description></item><item><title>My time in Utrecht</title><link>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2018/07/21/my-time-in-utrecht/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 17:58:21 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2018/07/21/my-time-in-utrecht/</guid><description>In the second half of 2015, about a year after finishing my undergradate degree, after spending six months in working in Burma for Rocket Internet, I was unsure of what to do with myself. One of the default options (for people like me) is to go into further education, which meant getting a graduate degree. This was something encouraged by both my parents and some (but not all) friends. I was unsure whether I wanted it, so I wrote down my own motivations for doing so:</description></item><item><title>Leaflet timeline in R</title><link>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2018/02/08/leaflet-timeline-in-r/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 15:52:58 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2018/02/08/leaflet-timeline-in-r/</guid><description>Leaflet is a powerful tool for visualasing spatial data in R. However, after much googling I could not find an easy way to create a timeline to visualise changes in time. Therefore, I decided to create a simple shiny app that does it.
Raw Android GPS Movements Code The code below takes raw location measurements from my Android phone visualises them over time. The size of the circle is the confidence interval of the measurement. Before you go and try to find me at those spots, I no longer live there!</description></item><item><title>Time Series analysis for Facebook message volume</title><link>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2017/12/17/time-series-analysis-for-facebook-message-volume/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2017 22:52:56 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2017/12/17/time-series-analysis-for-facebook-message-volume/</guid><description>Introduction to the data set The data is the amount of Facebook messages a user (me) sent and received between 2011 and 2016. The data was exported from Facebook, converted from HTML to JSON and subsequently read into R. For more details on how this was done, please consult here.
The original data source contains 413,101 timestamps and messages between 2008 and 2016. The volume of messages is very low between 2008-2011, and highly atypical to the rest of the series, so it was not considered in the sample.</description></item><item><title>Time Series analysis for Facebook message volume</title><link>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2017/12/01/time-series-analysis-for-facebook-message-volume/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 15:52:58 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2017/12/01/time-series-analysis-for-facebook-message-volume/</guid><description>Introduction to the data set
The data is the amount of Facebook messages a user (me) sent and received between 2011 and 2016. The data was exported from Facebook, converted from HTML to JSON and subsequently read into R. For more details on how this was done, please consult here.
The original data source contains 413,101 timestamps and messages between 2008 and 2016. The volume of messages is very low between 2008-2011, and highly atypical to the rest of the series, so it was not considered in the sample.</description></item><item><title>Raising money for friends hurt by Hurricane Irma</title><link>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2017/10/25/raising-money-for-friends-hurt-by-hurricane-irma/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 18:51:23 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2017/10/25/raising-money-for-friends-hurt-by-hurricane-irma/</guid><description>For the last year I have been helping people in Cuba sell tourism services online. In practice, this usually means creating accomodation listings on sites like Airbnb, messaging the guests and making sure the money gets to the hosts. About six months into doing this, I discovered a tool called Guesty which made things considerably easier (more on this in a bit).
In September due to Hurricane Irma came. Most guests cancelled their reservations. This in itself, put many of the people we work with in a financially difficult position.</description></item><item><title>Implementing a Kalman filter in R for Android GPS measurements</title><link>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2017/08/29/implementing-a-kalman-filter-in-r-for-android-gps-measurements/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2017 17:58:21 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2017/08/29/implementing-a-kalman-filter-in-r-for-android-gps-measurements/</guid><description>The problem I downloaded my data from Google Take-Out and have been playing around with it for my thesis. This is roughly what the data looks like after some pre-processing:
lon lat accuracy 5.115447 52.10574 877 5.115447 52.10574 877 5.113952 52.10451 18 5.115447 52.10574 877 5.115447 52.10574 877 5.115447 52.10574 877 As soon as I looked into it I realised there were some issues with the measurements. They were all over the place!
The circles are the measurements (with their radius representing the accuracy and the center being the point) and lines connect these measurements in time.</description></item><item><title>Costa Rican Saints</title><link>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2017/08/18/costa-rican-saints/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2017 22:22:16 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2017/08/18/costa-rican-saints/</guid><description>One of the first things a traveller notices when going to Costa Rica is that almost every town or city is named after a Saint. Growing up in Costa Rica, I just assumed this was something true of all Latin American countries, a legacy of Spanish colonial times. California has San Jose, San Fransisco, etc. I thought it was like that from California to Argentina.
After some travelling in Latin America I realised this was simply not true.</description></item><item><title>Bayesian Images</title><link>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2017/05/22/bayesian-images/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 22:22:16 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2017/05/22/bayesian-images/</guid><description>Graphs to accompany my poster presentation.
The data set The generated data is plotted below: Metropolis Hastings Algorithm This visual explanation of the Metropolis Hastings algorithm shows the proposal and the true density along with the Metropolis Hastings step. It was inspired and adapted from code by Balazs Torok.
Diagnostic Plots for Beta 2 via Gibbs Sampler Autocorrelation Plot The autocorrelations are negligable, suggesting good mixing.
Running Means Plot The running means have settled.
Three chain trace plot All three chains seem to be in the same place.</description></item><item><title>Thirteen hours in Rotterdam</title><link>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2017/01/11/thirteen-hours-in-rotterdam/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2017 11:32:32 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2017/01/11/thirteen-hours-in-rotterdam/</guid><description>Oscar Wilde once wrote:
“Whenever a man does a thoroughly stupid thing, it is always from the noblest motives.”
I bought a bus ticket from London to Rotterdam. I did this in order to save what effectively amounts to the price of a handful of beers in London prices. I needed to get to Budapest, and I already had a flight leaving from Rotterdam booked. I spent 8 excruciating hours on a bus from London Victoria to Rotterdam Centraal, to in Rotterdam at 5 am in a cold winter morning.</description></item><item><title>You are wasting your time with spreadsheets</title><link>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2016/11/13/you-are-wasting-your-time-with-spreadsheets/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 15:52:58 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2016/11/13/you-are-wasting-your-time-with-spreadsheets/</guid><description>This week I had an interesting conversation (as interesting as these conversations can get) about the use of spreadsheets in business. I am still a little bit surprised by how often they are used for things they are not really good for. Now, I don’t want to write about how there are better alternatives to spreadsheets. Instead, I’d like to illustrate how powerful non-spreadsheet tools are by describing a task I completed this week using R.</description></item><item><title>How to get your Facebook messages into R</title><link>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2016/10/29/how-to-get-your-facebook-messages-into-r/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2016 15:52:58 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2016/10/29/how-to-get-your-facebook-messages-into-r/</guid><description>It is a truism that we live in the information age, yet on a day to day basis we engage remarkably little with insights on the personal information we create. Sure, Netflix shows you films you want to see, Amazon offers books you want to buy and Facebook shows you pictures of cats with boobs or whatever it is you tend to click on, but explicit purpose of that is to get your money. What about using all that data to gain insights on who you are, who your friends are, what you tend to talk about?</description></item><item><title>Alphabetically inspired anecdotes from Cuba: 58 years after 1958</title><link>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2016/06/12/alphabetically-inspired-anecdotes-from-cuba-58-years-after-1958/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2016 11:32:32 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2016/06/12/alphabetically-inspired-anecdotes-from-cuba-58-years-after-1958/</guid><description>Aviacion de Cubana There was no toilet paper on the Russian-made Antonov 158 plane which took me and 15 other passengers to Havana. The Cuban state airline, Cubana de Aviacion, clearly does not need have to meet profitability targets. Even the dry sandwich they served tasted of an iron curtain.
Not unlike the other living political museum of China, immigration and customs is relatively straightforward. If you had to guess the political system of a country based on the border control procedures you’d probably guess the United States is authoritarian.</description></item><item><title>How I made this website - tutorial</title><link>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2016/04/20/how-i-made-this-website-tutorial/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 14:12:49 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2016/04/20/how-i-made-this-website-tutorial/</guid><description>Theory As our activities are increasingly organised online – from business through voting to leisure time – knowing how to write (or even just understand) code is an increasingly coveted skill. Its benefits range wide; if you can code you will get a better job, improve your analytical skills, make work processes easier and cheaper.
These reasons led us – Dora and Boaz, authors of this article – to set up our websites as a means of learning and practising a bit of coding.</description></item><item><title>Boaz's Review of Books: Violence, elaborate lies and a literary journey through China and Africa</title><link>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2016/04/18/boazs-review-of-books-violence-elaborate-lies-and-a-literary-journey-through-china-and-africa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2016 09:48:37 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2016/04/18/boazs-review-of-books-violence-elaborate-lies-and-a-literary-journey-through-china-and-africa/</guid><description>The books I finished reading recently that I thought might be interesting to comment upon were Steven Pinker’s The better Angels of Our Nature, Mo Yan’s Big Breast’s and Wide Hips, Kapuscinski’s The Shadow of the Sun, Robert Mazur’s Infiltrator and David Maurer’s Big Con . Steven Pinker, a psychologist at Harvard, wrote a (way too long) book to argue the world is becoming less, not more violent. What about ISIS, Ukraine, gang warfare and mass shootings?</description></item><item><title>Donald Trump and Zuckerberg's Matrix</title><link>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2016/02/29/donald-trump-and-zuckerbergs-matrix/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Feb 2016 22:22:16 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2016/02/29/donald-trump-and-zuckerbergs-matrix/</guid><description>Prediction markets have the Republican nomination for President of the USA going to billionaire reality TV host and megalomaniac Donald Trump. On the other side of the aisle, self-described socialist Sanders is making Hillary Clinton’s campaign sweat. This isn’t “politics as usual” for anyone except the writers of The Simpsons. According to the party decides theory (or at least my interpretation of Nate Silver’s interpretation) the party, as a loose coalition of opinion forming individuals, can heavily weigh in on who gets nominated.</description></item><item><title>Boaz's Review of Books</title><link>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2016/02/17/boazs-review-of-books/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2016 22:22:16 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2016/02/17/boazs-review-of-books/</guid><description>A few books I recently finished reading are Ben Bernanke&amp;rsquo;s Courage to act, Dr Philip Tetlock&amp;rsquo;s Superforecasting, Peter Thiel’s Zero to One, an unofficial biography on George Soros, and collection of druggie short stories titled Acid House by Irvine Welsh. I do not expect to do justice to the arguments in the books (read a real book review if you want that), I&amp;rsquo;m just sharing the lessons I learned from them as a little exercise.</description></item><item><title>What I read in 2015</title><link>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2015/12/27/what-i-read-in-2015/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2015 22:22:16 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2015/12/27/what-i-read-in-2015/</guid><description>I bought my Kindle slightly over a year ago, and since it has accompanied me everywhere I&amp;rsquo;ve been. It has provided me with entertainment on long journeys and education in subjects where I had none. I would like to share some of my favourite quotes. I have sorted them based on when I started reading them, with some slight editing.
December (2014) ﻿The Prince (Niccolò Machiavelli) Besides, pretexts for taking away the property are never wanting; for he who has once begun to live by robbery will always find pretexts for seizing what belongs to others; but reasons for taking life, on the contrary, are more difficult to find and sooner lapse.</description></item><item><title>Where I slept in 2015</title><link>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2015/12/22/where-i-slept-in-2015/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2015 22:22:16 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2015/12/22/where-i-slept-in-2015/</guid><description>This year has been an adventure. I&amp;rsquo;ve been on three continents, countless countries and dozens of cities. I thought it would be an interesting project to quantify it all by visualising on a map the places where I slept. This is the result: imgLeft: images/USA2015.png
In case you are interested in how I did it you can find the code below. I was inspired by this blog post.
library(readr) library(ggmap) library(&amp;quot;shiny&amp;quot;) days&amp;lt;-read_csv(&amp;quot;daysinayear/days.csv&amp;quot;)# spreadsheet with place in one column and days slept in another devtools::install_github(&amp;quot;bwlewis/rthreejs&amp;quot;) #First step: get lat and lng for where I've slept using Google Maps API x&amp;lt;-geocode(days$Location) days&amp;lt;-cbind(days,x) # Make a cool spinning globe globejs(img=&amp;quot;http://2.</description></item><item><title>The Migrant Crisis and Demography</title><link>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2015/11/05/the-migrant-crisis-and-demography/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2015 22:22:16 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2015/11/05/the-migrant-crisis-and-demography/</guid><description>In September, images of anti-riot police in a standoff with desperate migrants were shown on television, inspiring many people to volunteer and even more people to chatter about the situation. Yet the problem with our handling of crises is that we often wait for one to happen before doing anything (even just notice something is amiss). Humans are vulnerable to overlooking gradual phenomena with no easily distinguishable onset. There is an ongoing global demographic transition and it will influence most shifts in the next 25 years, be it in politics, business or international relations.</description></item><item><title>Using Google Maps API: Mol Bubi Competition</title><link>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2015/11/05/using-google-maps-api-mol-bubi-competition/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2015 11:36:16 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2015/11/05/using-google-maps-api-mol-bubi-competition/</guid><description>A few friends and I are involved in the Budapest public bicycle data science competition. As of right now we are in the top ten, although in all honesty, it hasn&amp;rsquo;t really started yet. We signed a non-disclosure agreement, so I cannot really share any cool details. What I can share however, is the function I wrote in R to get calculate the distances and duration of bike trips using Google Maps&amp;rsquo; API.
#distance calucations #### This script uses RCurl and RJSONIO to download data from Google's API library(RCurl) library(RJSONIO) #define api key as: api&amp;lt;-&amp;quot;YOURAPI&amp;quot; #the function assumes address input in following dataframe: #lat1,lng1,lat2,lng2 DistDur &amp;lt;- function(address,time = as.</description></item><item><title>Myanmar 2015</title><link>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2015/10/26/myanmar-2015/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2015 11:36:16 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2015/10/26/myanmar-2015/</guid><description>I spent six amazing months in Myanmar (Burma). Here&amp;rsquo;s a video of my adventures with monkeys, monks and motorcycles.</description></item><item><title>Do stupid people make more spelling mistakes? An analysis with R.</title><link>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2015/10/20/do-stupid-people-make-more-spelling-mistakes-an-analysis-with-r./</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2015 10:23:55 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2015/10/20/do-stupid-people-make-more-spelling-mistakes-an-analysis-with-r./</guid><description>English orthography is a tricky topic. Most people learning English (and a great number of native speakers) are puzzled by a written language with an utter disregard for phonemic representation. It is therefore very worrying that individuals intuitively assume making orthographic mistakes is a sign of low intelligence or unprofessionalism. In this post we are going to show how we looked into the relationship of IQ and orthography using R. We are going to need two things:</description></item><item><title>Don't fear foreign education</title><link>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2012/11/20/dont-fear-foreign-education/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2012 15:52:58 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/2012/11/20/dont-fear-foreign-education/</guid><description>Startling new data show that emigration out of Hungary is at a 20-year record high and that many more Hungarians have seriously considered leaving Hungary to live, work, or study in another member state of the EU. But instead of speaking ominously about the potentially catastrophic consequences of such emigration trends for Hungary, it is useful to think of this increased mobility as a potentially positive phenomenon.
Geographic mobility is often an indicator of social mobility.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/1/01/01/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sobradob.github.io/blog/1/01/01/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>