<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Opinion on Boaz Sobrado's Website</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/categories/opinion/</link><description>Recent content in Opinion on Boaz Sobrado's Website</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&amp;copy; 2024 &lt;a href="https://www.boazsobrado.com/">Boaz Sobrado&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 13:11:22 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://boazsobrado.com/categories/opinion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Crypto Should Disrupt Current Anti-Money Laundering Practices, Not Adopt Them</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2022/03/31/crypto-should-disrupt-current-anti-money-laundering-practices-not-adopt-them/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2022/03/31/crypto-should-disrupt-current-anti-money-laundering-practices-not-adopt-them/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Originally published in &lt;a href="https://www.coindesk.com/layer2/2022/03/31/crypto-should-disrupt-current-anti-money-laundering-practices-not-adopt-them/">CoinDesk&lt;/a>&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Until the early 20th century, highly respected doctors would routinely engage in bloodletting to cure ailments ranging from acne to tuberculosis. While we have left bloodletting behind, we are still engaging in putatively helpful, but veritably destructive practices.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Modern know-your-customer/anti-money laundering (KYC/AML) regulations are equivalent to financial bloodletting today: They do little good and may cause a lot of harm. Yet whether we like it or not, the KYC/AML nightmare is coming to crypto.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>GameFi’s Promise and Reality Are Still Worlds Apart</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2022/03/08/gamefis-promise-and-reality-are-still-worlds-apart/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2022/03/08/gamefis-promise-and-reality-are-still-worlds-apart/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Originally published in &lt;a href="https://www.coindesk.com/layer2/2022/03/08/gamefis-promise-and-reality-are-still-worlds-apart/">CoinDesk&lt;/a>&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Among crypto&amp;rsquo;s hottest trends is GameFi, which brings Web 3&amp;rsquo;s advantages to gaming. Web 3&amp;rsquo;s meaning &lt;a href="https://cobie.substack.com/p/wtf-is-web3">varies&lt;/a> by individual but reflects rising demand among people who are spending more time and money in meta worlds to own their virtual assets, free from the interference of platform developers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But are strong in-game property rights compatible with fun, escapist experiences that users are seeking?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Skeptics are not convinced. They say that GameFi games are not fun but rather merely repackaged versions of the worst elements of decentralized finance (&lt;a href="https://www.coindesk.com/learn/what-is-defi/">DeFi&lt;/a>). Play-to-earn games, some skeptics say, suffer because they are &lt;a href="https://frankmuci.substack.com/p/are-play-to-earn-p2e-games-pyramid?r=69dfl&amp;amp;utm_campaign=post&amp;amp;utm_medium=web">more or less pyramid&lt;/a> schemes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Are Crypto Investors Savvy or Suckers? The UK’s Tax and Financial Regulators Don’t Agree</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2022/02/24/are-crypto-investors-savvy-or-suckers-the-uks-tax-and-financial-regulators-dont-agree/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2022/02/24/are-crypto-investors-savvy-or-suckers-the-uks-tax-and-financial-regulators-dont-agree/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Originally published in &lt;a href="https://www.coindesk.com/layer2/2022/02/24/are-crypto-investors-savvy-or-suckers-the-uks-leading-tax-and-financial-regulators-dont-agree/">CoinDesk Magazine&lt;/a>&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Are crypto investors financially savvy investors who are capable of understanding the nuances of blockchain, Web 3 and &lt;a href="https://www.coindesk.com/learn/what-is-defi/">decentralized finance&lt;/a>? Or are they mostly vulnerable, uneducated speculators who are being taken advantage of?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.fca.org.uk/">The Financial Conduct Authority (FCA)&lt;/a>, the U.K.&amp;rsquo;s financial regulator, believes they are the latter, while the U.K.&amp;rsquo;s tax collection agency, &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/organisations/hm-revenue-customs">HM Revenue &amp;amp; Customs&lt;/a>, or HMRC, believes they are the former. While the agencies have issued a few helpful guidelines, their differing opinions underscore a fundamental inability to provide more sweeping and effective oversight that would protect consumers and ensure the industry&amp;rsquo;s development. Delays in finding such common ground are slowing progress on both fronts.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>We All Need to Stop Only Seeing the Dark Side of Crypto</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2021/12/19/we-all-need-to-stop-only-seeing-the-dark-side-of-crypto/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2021 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2021/12/19/we-all-need-to-stop-only-seeing-the-dark-side-of-crypto/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Originally published in &lt;a href="https://www.wired.com/story/crypto-remittances-cuba/">Wired Magazine&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>IN 2021, BITCOIN went mainstream. Wall Street set its eyes on the world of crypto, with hotshot investors like hedge funder Paul Tudor Jones leading the pack; &lt;em>The Economist&lt;/em> went from calling the cryptocurrency &lt;a href="https://www.economist.com/leaders/2018/08/30/bitcoin-and-other-cryptocurrencies-are-useless">&amp;ldquo;useless&amp;rdquo; in 2018&lt;/a> to arguing that it belongs in most portfolios; tech CEOs Jack Dorsey and Elon Musk gamely crossed swords about Bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s merits at a conference run by an asset management firm. Popular opinion lags a bit: Many people still believe cryptocurrency is a giant, global get-rich-quick scheme. Others simply dismiss the entire thing as a speculation-driven fad in the best case, a criminal enterprise in the worst. But amid the noise, the enthusiasm, and the hype, we might be losing the most important story: the way cryptocurrency is changing lives in the developing world.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>