<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>R on Boaz Sobrado's Website</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/categories/r/</link><description>Recent content in R on Boaz Sobrado's Website</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&amp;copy; 2022 &lt;a href="https://www.boazsobrado.com/">Boaz Sobrado&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 15:52:58 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://boazsobrado.com/categories/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Leaflet timeline in R</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2018/02/08/leaflet-timeline-in-r/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 15:52:58 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2018/02/08/leaflet-timeline-in-r/</guid><description>Leaflet is a powerful tool for visualasing spatial data in R. However, after much googling I could not find an easy way to create a timeline to visualise changes in time. Therefore, I decided to create a simple shiny app that does it.
Raw Android GPS Movements Code The code below takes raw location measurements from my Android phone visualises them over time. The size of the circle is the confidence interval of the measurement. Before you go and try to find me at those spots, I no longer live there!</description></item><item><title>Time Series analysis for Facebook message volume</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2017/12/01/time-series-analysis-for-facebook-message-volume/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 15:52:58 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2017/12/01/time-series-analysis-for-facebook-message-volume/</guid><description>Introduction to the data setThe data is the amount of Facebook messages a user (me) sent and received between 2011 and 2016. The data was exported from Facebook, converted from HTML to JSON and subsequently read into R. For more details on how this was done, please consult here.
The original data source contains 413,101 timestamps and messages between 2008 and 2016. The volume of messages is very low between 2008-2011, and highly atypical to the rest of the series, so it was not considered in the sample.</description></item><item><title>Implementing a Kalman filter in R for Android GPS measurements</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2017/08/29/implementing-a-kalman-filter-in-r-for-android-gps-measurements/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2017 17:58:21 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2017/08/29/implementing-a-kalman-filter-in-r-for-android-gps-measurements/</guid><description>The problem I downloaded my data from Google Take-Out and have been playing around with it for my thesis. This is roughly what the data looks like after some pre-processing:
lon lat accuracy 5.115447 52.10574 877 5.115447 52.10574 877 5.113952 52.10451 18 5.115447 52.10574 877 5.115447 52.10574 877 5.115447 52.10574 877 As soon as I looked into it I realised there were some issues with the measurements. They were all over the place!
The circles are the measurements (with their radius representing the accuracy and the center being the point) and lines connect these measurements in time.</description></item><item><title>Costa Rican Saints</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2017/08/18/costa-rican-saints/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2017 22:22:16 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2017/08/18/costa-rican-saints/</guid><description>One of the first things a traveller notices when going to Costa Rica is that almost every town or city is named after a Saint. Growing up in Costa Rica, I just assumed this was something true of all Latin American countries, a legacy of Spanish colonial times. California has San Jose, San Fransisco, etc. I thought it was like that from California to Argentina.
After some travelling in Latin America I realised this was simply not true.</description></item><item><title>Bayesian Images</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2017/05/22/bayesian-images/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 22:22:16 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2017/05/22/bayesian-images/</guid><description>Graphs to accompany my poster presentation.
The data set The generated data is plotted below: Metropolis Hastings Algorithm This visual explanation of the Metropolis Hastings algorithm shows the proposal and the true density along with the Metropolis Hastings step. It was inspired and adapted from code by Balazs Torok.
Diagnostic Plots for Beta 2 via Gibbs Sampler Autocorrelation Plot The autocorrelations are negligable, suggesting good mixing.
Running Means Plot The running means have settled.
Three chain trace plot All three chains seem to be in the same place.</description></item><item><title>You are wasting your time with spreadsheets</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2016/11/13/you-are-wasting-your-time-with-spreadsheets/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 15:52:58 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2016/11/13/you-are-wasting-your-time-with-spreadsheets/</guid><description>This week I had an interesting conversation (as interesting as these conversations can get) about the use of spreadsheets in business. I am still a little bit surprised by how often they are used for things they are not really good for. Now, I don’t want to write about how there are better alternatives to spreadsheets. Instead, I’d like to illustrate how powerful non-spreadsheet tools are by describing a task I completed this week using R.</description></item><item><title>How to get your Facebook messages into R</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2016/10/29/how-to-get-your-facebook-messages-into-r/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2016 15:52:58 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2016/10/29/how-to-get-your-facebook-messages-into-r/</guid><description>It is a truism that we live in the information age, yet on a day to day basis we engage remarkably little with insights on the personal information we create. Sure, Netflix shows you films you want to see, Amazon offers books you want to buy and Facebook shows you pictures of cats with boobs or whatever it is you tend to click on, but explicit purpose of that is to get your money. What about using all that data to gain insights on who you are, who your friends are, what you tend to talk about?</description></item><item><title>Where I slept in 2015</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2015/12/22/where-i-slept-in-2015/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2015 22:22:16 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2015/12/22/where-i-slept-in-2015/</guid><description>This year has been an adventure. I&amp;rsquo;ve been on three continents, countless countries and dozens of cities. I thought it would be an interesting project to quantify it all by visualising on a map the places where I slept. This is the result: imgLeft: images/USA2015.png
In case you are interested in how I did it you can find the code below. I was inspired by this blog post.
library(readr) library(ggmap) library(&amp;quot;shiny&amp;quot;) days&amp;lt;-read_csv(&amp;quot;daysinayear/days.csv&amp;quot;)# spreadsheet with place in one column and days slept in another devtools::install_github(&amp;quot;bwlewis/rthreejs&amp;quot;) #First step: get lat and lng for where I've slept using Google Maps API x&amp;lt;-geocode(days$Location) days&amp;lt;-cbind(days,x) # Make a cool spinning globe globejs(img=&amp;quot;http://2.</description></item><item><title>Using Google Maps API: Mol Bubi Competition</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2015/11/05/using-google-maps-api-mol-bubi-competition/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2015 11:36:16 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2015/11/05/using-google-maps-api-mol-bubi-competition/</guid><description>A few friends and I are involved in the Budapest public bicycle data science competition. As of right now we are in the top ten, although in all honesty, it hasn&amp;rsquo;t really started yet. We signed a non-disclosure agreement, so I cannot really share any cool details. What I can share however, is the function I wrote in R to get calculate the distances and duration of bike trips using Google Maps&amp;rsquo; API.
#distance calucations #### This script uses RCurl and RJSONIO to download data from Google's API library(RCurl) library(RJSONIO) #define api key as: api&amp;lt;-&amp;quot;YOURAPI&amp;quot; #the function assumes address input in following dataframe: #lat1,lng1,lat2,lng2 DistDur &amp;lt;- function(address,time = as.</description></item><item><title>Do stupid people make more spelling mistakes? An analysis with R.</title><link>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2015/10/20/do-stupid-people-make-more-spelling-mistakes-an-analysis-with-r./</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2015 10:23:55 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://boazsobrado.com/blog/2015/10/20/do-stupid-people-make-more-spelling-mistakes-an-analysis-with-r./</guid><description>English orthography is a tricky topic. Most people learning English (and a great number of native speakers) are puzzled by a written language with an utter disregard for phonemic representation. It is therefore very worrying that individuals intuitively assume making orthographic mistakes is a sign of low intelligence or unprofessionalism. In this post we are going to show how we looked into the relationship of IQ and orthography using R. We are going to need two things:</description></item></channel></rss>