<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>cuba on Boaz Sobrado's Website</title><link>https://sobradob.github.io/personal_site_2022/tags/cuba/</link><description>Recent content in cuba on Boaz Sobrado's Website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&amp;copy; 2022 &lt;a href="https://www.boazsobrado.com/">Boaz Sobrado&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 13:11:22 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sobradob.github.io/personal_site_2022/tags/cuba/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Films watched in 2022</title><link>https://sobradob.github.io/personal_site_2022/blog/2023/01/01/films-watched-in-2022/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://sobradob.github.io/personal_site_2022/blog/2023/01/01/films-watched-in-2022/</guid><description>Satantango A seven hour long Hungarian film marathon by Béla Tarr.
This film is shown surprisingly often in London, usually with two intermissions.
The Queen of Spades A quaint oldie film, fairly well done.
The Room Watching this was a lot of fun. Big cult following at the cinema, the audience was shouting out every line. You get spoons when stepping in as well.
Jackie Brown A Tartantino classic. Some say its his best, but apparently if you say this to Quentin&amp;rsquo;s face he&amp;rsquo;ll get angry at you.</description></item><item><title>On The Brink - On Bitcoin adoption trends in Cuba</title><link>https://sobradob.github.io/personal_site_2022/blog/2021/06/04/on-the-brink-on-bitcoin-adoption-trends-in-cuba/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://sobradob.github.io/personal_site_2022/blog/2021/06/04/on-the-brink-on-bitcoin-adoption-trends-in-cuba/</guid><description/></item><item><title>A day using money in Cuba</title><link>https://sobradob.github.io/personal_site_2022/blog/2020/05/22/a-day-using-money-in-cuba/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://sobradob.github.io/personal_site_2022/blog/2020/05/22/a-day-using-money-in-cuba/</guid><description>Ira wakes up craving some eggs for breakfast. She walks under the strong Cuban sun and visits the food market . She&amp;rsquo;s lucky: they have eggs today.
&amp;ldquo;How much for the box?&amp;rdquo; she asks, pointing at the box of 30 eggs.
&amp;ldquo;Four pesos&amp;rdquo;
She looks in her purse and finds a 100 peso note. She hands the note to the seller, who nods and hands her the eggs. She leaves without getting any change, nor did she expect to.</description></item><item><title>Cuba’s short term property rental market 2017-2018</title><link>https://sobradob.github.io/personal_site_2022/blog/2018/08/11/cubas-short-term-property-rental-market-2017-2018/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2018 13:11:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://sobradob.github.io/personal_site_2022/blog/2018/08/11/cubas-short-term-property-rental-market-2017-2018/</guid><description>In July of 2017 President Trump announced with much fanfare a new policy towards Cuba. This was following the Obama administrations &amp;ldquo;thaw&amp;rdquo; in Cuban-American bilateral relations, which had lead to a noticable rise in Americas visiting the island. Then more bad news for the Cuban tourism industry:
sonic warfare in the news hurricanes All of this together had a noticable impact on the Cuban tourism sector. Official Cuban statistics show that tourism numbers are going up.</description></item><item><title>Alphabetically inspired anecdotes from Cuba: 58 years after 1958</title><link>https://sobradob.github.io/personal_site_2022/blog/2016/06/12/alphabetically-inspired-anecdotes-from-cuba-58-years-after-1958/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2016 11:32:32 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://sobradob.github.io/personal_site_2022/blog/2016/06/12/alphabetically-inspired-anecdotes-from-cuba-58-years-after-1958/</guid><description>Aviacion de Cubana There was no toilet paper on the Russian-made Antonov 158 plane which took me and 15 other passengers to Havana. The Cuban state airline, Cubana de Aviacion, clearly does not need have to meet profitability targets. Even the dry sandwich they served tasted of an iron curtain.
Not unlike the other living political museum of China, immigration and customs is relatively straightforward. If you had to guess the political system of a country based on the border control procedures you’d probably guess the United States is authoritarian.</description></item></channel></rss>